-==http://www.1000fr.net==-
謦靈風軟影視論壇榮譽出品
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
www.1000fr.net presents
你知不知道 中國的天才
You know there are more people with genius IQ living in China
比美國人口還要多
than they're people of any kind living in United States.
- 這不可能 - 真的
- That can't be possible be true. - That is.
為什麼呢？
What would account for that?
首先 中國的人口多
First, awful lot people living in China.
但我的問題是
But, here's my question.
在那些SAT考滿分的人中 你如何讓自己與別不同呢？
How do you distinguish yourself than population of people who all got 1600 under SAT's?
- 中國不考SAT吧 - 沒錯
- I didn't know they take SAT's in China. - They don't.
但我說的不是中國 是我自己
I wasn't talkin' about China anymore. I was talkin' about me.
- 你考了滿分？ - 對
- You got 1600? - Yes.
我本可以去合唱團的 但我不會唱歌
I can sing in a Capella group, but I can't sing.
也就是你SAT一道題都沒錯
Does that mean you actually got nothing wrong?
我可以劃賽艇 也可以發明25美元的電腦
I could row crew or invent a 25 dollar PC.
或者加入終極俱樂部？
Or you get into the "Final Club"?
對 也可以加入終極俱樂部
Or I get into the "Final Club".
從女人的角度來看 男人不加入是件好事
You know, from women perspective sometimes, not seeing a man in is a good thing.
- 我沒開玩笑 - 不過我還挺喜歡男生劃賽艇的
- This is serious. - On the other hand, I do like a row crew.
呃 那玩意我弄不來
Well, I can't do that.
- 我開玩笑的 - 我SAT一道題都沒錯
- I was kidding. - Yes, I got nothing wrong in test.
那你有試過嗎？
Have you ever tried?
- 我正嘗試著呢 - 嘗試加入賽艇隊？
- I'm trying right now. - To row crew?
是終極俱樂部 怎麼會是賽艇隊 才不 你是不是誤會了
Gettin' into "Final Club". To row crew? No! Are you like... whatever, delusional?
可能吧 有時候你兩件事一塊說
Maybe, sometimes you said 2 things at once,
我就抓不住你的重點了…
I'm not sure which one I suppose to be aiming at...
不過你見過劃賽艇的人 對吧
But you seen guys who row crew, right?
- 沒啊 - 好吧 他們比我壯
- No. - Ok, well, they bigger than me.
都是世界級的運動員
They world class athlete.
你剛剛還說喜歡劃賽艇的
Like a second ago you said you like guys who row crew.
所以我想你該見過
So I assumed you've met one.
我就是那意思 就像女孩都喜歡牛仔一樣
I guess, I just meant like the idea of it, you know the way a girl likes cowboys.
好吧
Ok.
我們是不是應該點些吃的
Should we get something to eat?
你想不想談點別的
Would you like to talk about something else?
不 只是從討論終極俱樂部開始
No, it just that since the beginning of the conversation about the "Finals Club"
我就覺得時間過得很快
I think I may have miss a birthday.
中國天才真的比美國的總人口…
There are really more people in China with genius IQ's than entire...
鳳凰俱樂部最多元化 還有福萊俱樂部 羅斯福加的是坡客
"Phoenix" is the most diverse. The "Fry Club", Roosevelt punched the porc.
哪個羅斯福？
Which one?
坡斯廉俱樂部 也叫坡客 是最頂尖的
"The Porcellian, the Porc, it's the best of the best"
我是問哪個羅斯福？
Which Roosevelt?
西奧多.羅斯福
Theodore
是不是他們真用大巴去接…
Is it true they send a bus around to pick up the girls?
想和下任鳳凰俱樂部主席開派對的姑娘啊
Who wanna party with next phoenix chairman.
你懂為什麼我想去那了吧
So you can see why it's so important to get in.
好吧 哪個是最容易加的
Well, which is the easiest to get into?
你為什麼問我這個
Why would you ask me that?
就隨便問問
I was just asking.
沒有容易的  這才是關鍵
None of them. That's the point.
我朋友愛德華多 去年夏天 靠投機石油期貨賺了三十萬
My friend, Eduardo made $300.000 betting oil futures one summer.
可他想進去還差得遠呢
And Eduardo won't comes close to get in.
這堛漱H根本不看重掙錢的能力
The ability to make money doesn't impress anybody around here.
他一定很厲害 一夏天掙了三十萬啊
Must be nice. He made $300.000 in a summer.
- 他喜歡氣象學 - 你剛才不是還說石油期貨嗎
- He likes meteorology. - You said it was oil futures.
你要是能預知天氣 你就能預測燃油的價格
You can read the weather, you can predict the price of heating oil.
你剛才那麼問我 是不是覺得 只有最容易進的終極俱樂部
I think you ask me that because you think the "Final Club" that's easiest to get into is the one,
我才有希望啊
where I'll have the best chance...
什麼
What?
你問我哪個是最容易進的
You ask me which one is the easiest to get into
因為你覺得我進那個的可能性最大
Because you think that the one, where I have the best chance.
你容易進
The one that the easiest is to get into,
別人也容易進啊
Would be the one where anybody has the best chance.
你問的不是哪個是最好的
You didn't ask me which one was the best one.
你問我哪個是最容易進的
You ask me which one was the easiest one.
我就那麼一問 好吧
I was honestly just asking, ok...
就那麼一問…
I was just asking to ask...
- 馬克 我沒別的意思 - 艾瑞卡
- Mark, I'm not speaking in code. - Erika,
你已經沉迷在終極俱樂部了
You obsesses with "Finals Clubs"
你得了終極俱樂部強迫癥 你得找個醫生看看
You have "Finals Clubs" - OCD  You need to see someone about it.
讓他給你開點藥
who'll prescribe you some sort of medication
反正你也不在乎副作用會不會讓你失明
You don't care if the side effect may include blindness.
是終極俱樂部 不是決賽俱樂部
"Final Clubs" not "Finals Clubs"
而且沉湎其中和積極進取是不一樣的
And there's a difference between being obsessed than being motivated.
沒錯 是不一樣
Yes, there is.
你就是這樣 你剛剛就是話埵雩
Well, you do that, it's was cryptic, so you do speaking code.
我沒想說別的
I didn't mean to be cryptic.
我所要說的就是我需要做點大事 好讓他們注意到我
I'm just saying I need to do something substantial in order to get the attention of the club.
為什麼
Why?
因為那地方獨一無二 樂趣橫生
Because they're exclusive and fun.
而且能讓我過的更好
And they lead to the better life.
泰迪羅斯福選上美國總統
Teddy Roosevelt didn't get elected for the president
- 也不是因為他是鳳凰俱樂部的啊 - 就是這個原因 還有 他是坡斯廉的
- because he was member from "Phoenix" Club? - He was a member of The Porcellian, and yes he did.
你怎麼不集中精力做你最好的自己呢
Why don't you just concentrate on being the best you, you can be.
你真這麼覺得
Did you really just said that?
開玩笑的
I was kidding.
- 我就是陳述事實 一點也不過分 - 我就和你直說吧
- *** - I wanna try to be straight forward
我覺得你應該支持我
*** You might wanna be a little more supportive.
如果我進了俱樂部 我就能帶你去參加各種聚會活動
If I get in I will be taking you to the events
還可以介紹很多你平時見不到的人物認識
and the gatherings and will be meeting a lot of people you won't normally get to meet.
你真打算這樣嗎
You would do that for me?
你是我女朋友啊
We're dating.
好吧
Ok,
那我也和你直說吧 咱倆完了
well I wanna try and be straight forward even let you know that we're not anymore.
你什麼意思
What you mean?
我們不再是男女朋友了 對不起
We're not dating anymore. I'm sorry.
- 開玩笑的吧 - 我認真的
- This is a joke? - No, it's not.
你要跟我分手
You're breaking up with me?
你要介紹我認識一些我平時見不到的人物
You gonna introduce me the people I wouldn't normally have the chance to meet.
這他媽…
What the f...
- 這到底什麼意思啊？ - 淡定點
- What is that supposed to mean? - Wait, settle down.
我什麼意思？
What is it supposed to mean?
艾瑞卡 我們之所以坐在這喝一杯
Erica, the reason we're able to sit and drink right now,
是因為你過去和看門那傢伙上過床
because you used to sleep with the door guy.
他叫鮑比
"The door guy" his name is Bobby.
我沒跟他上過床
I have not slept with "the door guy".
他是我的一個朋友
"The door guy" is a friend of mine.
而且他是個好人
And he's the perfectly good class of people.
你就出身名門嗎？
And what part of Long Island you from? Wimbledon?
- 別別 你真生氣了 - 我回去了
- Wait,Wait, wait is this real? - I'm going back to my dormy.
- 是的 - 那好吧 我道歉還不行
- Yes. - Ok, than wait, I apologize, ok...
- 我要去看書了 - 艾瑞卡…
- I have to go study. - Erika...
- 怎麼 - 我真心的道歉
- Yes? - I'm sorry, I meant it.
我很滿意 但我真得回去學習了
I appreciate that but I have to go study.
別這樣 你回去也不學習
Come on. You don't have to study.
何必回去呢 我們談談吧
You don't have to study. Let just talk.
- 不行 - 為什麼
- I can't - Why?
因為我累了 跟你約會 就像和跑步機約會一樣
Because it is exhausting. Dating you is like dating a stairmaster.
我就是說 你現在用不著…
All I meant is that you not likely to...
我不是說你爸媽
Currently, I wasn't making a comment on you're parents.
我就是說你去的是波士頓大學
I was saying that you go to B.U. *Boston University*
我就是陳述事實 就這樣
I was studying a fact. That's all.
如果你認為我太粗魯 我還是會道歉的
If it's seem rude, than of course I've to apologize.
- 我要去看書了 - 你不用看的
- I have to go study. - You don't have to study.
- 你為什麼總說我不用學習啊 - 因為你就念個波士頓大學而已
- Why you keep saying that I don't need to study. - Because you go to B.U.
想吃點什麼嗎
Wanna get some food?
非常抱歉我的教育程度沒能讓您滿意
I'm sorry you're not sufficiently impressed with my educations.
我也很抱歉 因為我沒有賽艇
I'm sorry, I don't have a row boat.
- 那我們扯平了 - 我想我們還是做朋友吧
- So we're even. - I think we should just be friend.
我不缺朋友
I don't want friends.
我也就是客氣下 我一點也不想和你做朋友
I was just being polite. I have no intention of being friends with you...
操作系統課讓我壓力很大
I'm under some pressure right now from my OS class.
點些吃的吧 或許我們就能…
If could just order some food. I think we should...
或許你以後在電腦行業會大有作為
Look, you will probably going to be very successful computer person.
你一輩子都會覺得
You gonna go thru life thinking that girls don't like you,
女孩子不喜歡你是因為你是書獃子
Because you're a nerd...
但我真心的說 你錯了
I want you know, from the bottom of my heart that won't be true.
那是因為你是個混蛋
It would be because you are an asshole.
-==http://www.1000fr.net==- 謦靈風軟影視論壇榮譽出品 本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
www.1000fr.net presents
-=風軟FRM字幕組=- 翻譯: 何意難平 Mico 超大碗艾瑪 校對: 小虎 時間軸：VinE
Sync:VinE
社交網絡
The Social Network
哈佛大學 秋天 2003年
Harvard University, Fall 2003
科克蘭公寓
Kirkland House
晚上8點13分
8:13 PM
艾瑞卡·奧布萊特就是個賤貨
Erika Albright's a bitch
你這麼說 是因為她家之前姓奧布萊希特
You think that's because her family changed their name from Albrecht?
還是你覺得所有波士頓大學的女生都是婊子呢
Or do you think because all B.U. girls are bitches?
鄭重聲明 她也許看著有34C
For the record, she may look like a 34C.
但那全是豐胸內衣的功勞
but she's getting all kind of help from our friends at "Victoria's Secret"
她只有34B 而且堶探N像飛機場一樣
She's a 34B, as in barely anything there.
虛假廣告害死人
False Advertising.
晚上 9點48分
9:48 PM
事實上她臉蛋還不錯
The truth is she has a nice face.
我得幹點什麼轉移注意力
I need to do something to take my mind of her.
說著容易 但我得先有個辦法
Easy enough, except I need an idea.
我有點喝醉了 我不會撒謊的
I'm a little intoxicated. I'm not gonna lie.
就算是無聊的週二 還沒到十點 又有什麼關係呢
So, what if it's not even 10pm and it's a Tuesday night?
科克蘭的Facebook開在我桌面上
The Kirkland's facebook is open on my desktop
有人上傳了不少雷人的照片
And somebody of these people with pretty horrendous facebook pics.
坐在那的比利·奧羅森出了個主意
Billy Olsen's sitting here had the idea,
說把這些照片和家禽家畜放在一起
putting some of the picture next to picture of farm animal,
然後讓大家投票看哪個更火
and have people vote who's hotter.
這主意不錯啊 奧羅森先生
Good call, Mr. Olsen!
好的 開始
Yeah, it's on.
我不想和家禽家畜比 但我覺得拿兩個人比不錯
I'm not gonna do the farm animal but I like the idea of comparing two people together.
因為這比Hotornot.com上 給性感程度直接打分的方式更含蓄
It gives the whole thing a very "Turing" feel since people's rating of the picture is more implicit...
給人一種"圖靈機"的感覺 (存儲量沒有限制的理論計算機)
Than say, choosing a number to represent each person's hotness like they do on hotornot. com
首先我們需要許多照片
The first thing we're going to need is a lot of picture
不幸的是哈佛沒有統一公開的照片庫
Unfortunately, Harvard doesn't keep a public centralized facebook,
所以我將從各自宿舍電腦盜取他們照片
So I'm going to get all the images from the individual houses that people are in,
黑客登場
Let the hacking begin!
從科克蘭開始 這堛漱@切都是公開的 還允許在Apache系統中奡﹞J目錄
First up is Kirkland, they keep everything open and allow indexes in their Apache configuration,
所以用個WGET就能下載 科克蘭全部的照片庫圖片了
So a little wget magic is all that's necessary to download the entire Kirkland facebook.
易如反掌
Kid's stuff.
下來是伊利爾特 他們也是公開的 但在Apache上加不了目錄
Next is Eliot. They're also open, but with no indexes in Apache.
我進行一個空白搜索 接著數據庫堛漫狾章洃驦N會顯示出來
I can run an empty search and it returns all of the images in the database in a single page.
然後我保存網頁 火狐就會幫我存好照片
Then I can save the page and Mozilla will save all the images for me.
不錯 進展順利
Excellent. Moving right along.
請注意
Excuse me, everybody...
你們現在所在的是 全世界最古老最有特色俱樂部
You're in one of the oldest, one of the most exclusive club, not just Harvard but in the world.
現在我宣佈鳳凰俱樂部秋季學期首場派對開始
Now, I wanna welcome you all, The Phoenix Club First Party of the fall semester.
洛厄爾有安全防護 需要用戶名和密碼
Lowell has some security they require username/password combo.
我可以直接進入 而且說他們沒有FAS用戶權限
I'm gonna go ahead and says the don't have an access to main fas user database
所以他們看不到這次入侵
So they have no worry detecting an intrusion.
亞當斯沒有安全系統 且每頁只能顯示20個結果
Adams has no security but limit the number of result to 20 of pages,
我再用一次對付洛厄爾的辦法就能搞定
All I need to do is to break up some script I use on Lowell and reset.
昆西都沒有在線的Facebook 真寒磣
Quincy has no online facebook, what a shame!
這我也沒辦法
Nothing I can do about that.
頓斯特不太好弄 他們不是沒公共目錄 他們壓根就沒目錄
Dunster is intense not only there's no public directory but there's no directory at all.
你必須進行搜索 而且每次超過二十個結果 就什麼都不會顯示
You have to do searches. And if you're search return more than 20 matches, nothing's get return.
一旦有個結果 也不會直接連接到圖片
Once you do get result, they don't link directly to images.
而是連接到個人網頁或別的什麼
They link to PHP that redirect to something.
很奇怪 估計不太容易 我一會再弄
Weird! That's maybe difficult, I'll come back later.
- 馬克 謝爾頓醒了 - 怎麼了
- Hei, Mark! - What?
- 做的好 魚很不錯 - 謝了
- Great one. Beautiful fish. - Thanks.
埃弗雷特稍好點 雖然還是要搜索
Leverett is a little better. They still make you search.
空白搜索會鏈接到有每個學生照片的網頁上
But you can do an empty search and get links to pages with every students pictures
噁心的是 每次只能打開一張
I slightly obnoxious that they only let you view one picture at a time...
我不可能打開五百個網頁 下載一百次照片
There's no way I'm gonna go to 500 pages to download pics one at a time
所以有必要退出EMACS 修改Perl代碼
So it's definitely necessary to break out emacs and modify that Perl script.
凌晨 2點08分
***
搞定
Done.
怎樣了
Hey, what's goin' on?
時機正好 愛德華多來了
Perfect timing.
他有我最需要的東西
Eduardo is here and he is going to have the key ingredients
- 馬克 - 愛德華多…
- Hey Mark, - Eduardo...
你和艾瑞卡分手了？
You and Erica split up?
你怎麼知道的
How did you know that?
你博客上都寫著呢
It's on your blog.
- 好吧 - 你還好吧
- Yeah. - Are you alright?
- 我要你幫忙 - 我就是幹這個來的
- I need you. - I'm here for you.
不是要你安慰我 我需要你投機石油時用的公式
No, I need the algorithm you use to rank chess players.
你沒事兒吧
Are you ok?
我們在給女孩打分
We're ranking girls.
- 你說女學生嗎 - 對
- You mean others student. -Yup.
你覺得這是個好主意嗎
You think this such a good idea?
我需要那個運算公式
I need the algorithm, alright. I need the algorithm.
每個女生有1400的基礎分
Each girl base rating 1400.
在某一時刻女孩A得到R-a的評分 女孩B得到R-b的評分
At any given time "Girl A" has a rating R-a and "Girl B" has a rating R-b.
當對任意兩個女孩進行評比時
When any 2 girls are matched up,
會根據已有的分數進行的評測
there's an expectation of which will win based on their current rating, right?
沒錯 這些評測方法寫出來就是這樣
yeah.And all those expectations are express this way.
把這些寫成程序吧
Let's write it.
左邊的
The one on the left.
右邊的
The right.
***
- 搞定了 - 我們該先傳給誰呢
- It works. - Who should we send it first?
- 德懷恩 - 尼爾
- Dwyer - Neal
你想傳給誰
Who will you send it to?
唉 就那麼幾個人唄
Just to couple of people.
問題是 他們會傳給誰
Question is: who are they gonna send it to?
哥幾個 快過來看看
Hey, guys check this out.
這倆姑娘 左邊還是右邊
Right or left.
左邊那個
***
右邊還是左邊
Right or left.
左邊那個
*****
右邊還是左邊
Right or left.
那是我室友
She's my room mate.
悲劇啊
This is pathetic.
奧爾布賴特
Albright?
他寫了和你有關的博客
He blog about you.
你一定不想看到的
You don't wanna read it.
左邊的
***
還真是
*********
艾瑞卡 這是你的內衣嗎？ 我們從新生那堸膘茠
Erika, is this yours? ***
給我滾出去
***
流量真大啊
Awful lot of traffic.
你說我們是不是在它出事前收手啊
You think maybe we should shut it down before get into trouble.
喂
Hello?
慢點說 什麼事
Wa-wait... what?
在凌晨四點？
At 4 in the morning?
有個流量異常網站
Well, this very an usual amount of traffic to the switch of Kirkland.
不正常是說凌晨四點不該有那個流量嗎
You're saying it's unusual for 4 in the morning?
不 就算是在超級碗比賽中場休息時 這個流量也不正常
No, this should be unusual for half time at the superbowl.
好吧
Alright.
我有點急事
I'm gonna go in.
怎麼了？
What's goin' on?
哈佛的網絡要癱瘓了
Harvard network is about to crash.
你說不會是…
You don't think...
沒錯
I do...
看看別人的吧
Go to see if it's everybody...
都連不上
I can't comin'
網絡癱瘓了
The network's down.
如果不是巧合 我覺得這就是我們幹的
Unless, it's coincidence, I think this is us.
這不是巧合
It's not a coincidence.
媽的
Holy shit...
你就這樣被校委會叫去談話
So you were called in front of the Ad Board.
不是那樣的
That's not what happen.
你沒被校委會叫去啊
You weren't called in front of the Administrator Board?
我是說 在之前 我和艾瑞卡在酒吧那一晚
No, back, I mean... that's, back at the bar with Erica Albright.
- 她那麼說嗎 - 馬克
- She said all that? - Mark.
我跟她說了那樣的話嗎
That I said that stuff to her.
我就是在讀她的證詞啊
I was reading from the transcript for the deposition.
你們究竟為什麼要她作證啊？
Why we do even need to depose her?
這是我們的事
That really for us to decide.
你覺得如果她把我說的像個混蛋
Miss, You think if I know she can make me look like a jerk.
- 我就會妥協的話 你錯了 - 馬克…
- I'll be more likely to settle. - Mark...
我們休息一下 可以嗎
Why don't we stretch our legs for a minute, can we do that?
都連著3個小時了
It's been almost 3 hours.
老實說你浪費了那麼多時間
And frankly you did spend awful lot of the time...
就想用一個女孩在酒吧的證詞 讓扎克伯格先生難堪嗎？
Embarrassing Mr. Zuckerberg with the girl's testimony from the bar.
我沒覺得難堪 只是她說了很多假話
I'm not embarrassed. She just made a lot that up.
她發過誓的
She was under oath.
我猜她不是第一個發了誓以後做偽證的吧
I guess there would be the first time somebody's lies under oath.
兩個小時內點擊率就有兩千兩百多嗎
You got 22 hundred hits within 2 hours?
- 萬 - 什麼
- Thousands. - What?
兩萬兩千次
Twenty-two *thousands*.
他們真快啊
These guys are pretty fast.
有人能讓這比賽公平點嗎？
Sure anybody make this a fair fight?
咱們跳進水 游過去
Jump up and swim.
跳進去我們就淹死了
I think we'd have to jump up and drowned.
要不你向前劃 我向後
Or you could row forward, I could row backward.
我們是雙胞胎  科學上來說我們應該一樣啊
We're genetically identical, science says we'd stay in the one place.
老實划船吧
Just row the damn boat.
- 你聽說了嗎 - 什麼
- You guys here about this? - What?
兩天前的晚上 一名科克蘭的大二學生 用他的筆記本電腦弄癱了網絡
Two nights ago, a sophomore shut network from laptop at Kirkland.
- 真的 - 還是在凌晨四點
- *** - At 4AM.
他怎麼做到的
How?
他建了個評選最性感在校女生的網站
He set up a website, where you vote on the hotness female undergrads.
當時我們在幹嘛 怎麼沒聽說這事
What were we doing that none of us heard about this?
忘了 好像是早飯前三個小時皮艇訓練
*** Three hours rows before breakfast.
然後就去看書學習了
For course... Studying. ***
之後在泳池泡了三個小時 又繼續學習 也不知道怎麼就錯過了
***
那網站受歡迎嗎？
How much activity was on those thing?
兩萬兩千的流量
Twenty two thousands pages request.
兩萬兩千次？
***
這哥們黑了七棟樓的照片庫
This guy hack the facebook from 7 houses.
一晚上就建起了網站 當時他還喝醉了
He set up the whole site in 1 night. And he did it while he was drunk.
兩萬兩千
Twenty two thousands?
你怎麼知道他醉了
How do you know his drunk?
他一邊做網站 還一邊寫博客
He was blogging simultaneously,
- 你知道我怎麼想的嗎 - 說啊
- You know what I think? - I'm way ahead of you
我們應該把他拉進來
This is our guy.
卡梅隆·溫克艾沃斯 W-i-n-k-I-e-v-o-s-s 卡梅隆是普通拼法
Cameron Winklevoss, W-i-n-k-I-e-v-o-s-s, Cameron spell the usual way.
泰勒·溫克艾沃斯 泰勒是普通拼法 我和我哥哥同姓
Tyler Winklevoss, Tyler spell the usual way. And my last name the same as my brother's.
扎克伯格先生 這是行政委員會的聽證會
Mr. Zuckerberg, This in an Administration board hearing.
在建造www.facemash.com網站的過程中
You're being accused of intentionally breaching security, violating copyrights,
你涉嫌破壞安全系統 侵犯版權以及侵犯個人隱私
Violating individual privacy by creating the website www.facemash.com.
你還被控違反了學校傳播數碼照片的規定
You're also charge with being in violation university policy on distribution of digitized imaging.
在開始提問之前 你有權做自我陳述 你要那樣做嗎
Before we begin with our questioning you're allowed to make a statement, would you like to do so?
我已經在校報上道過歉了 對科林姆森 AVHW
I've, You know, I've already apologize to the Crimson, to the ABHW...
弗爾扎·拉提娜 和其他可能受到冒犯的哈佛女生
To Fuerza Latina, and to any women in Harvard may have been insulted as I take it that they were.
至於那些關於破壞安全系統的控訴
As for any charges stemming from the breach from the security,
我覺得委員會應該給予我一些認可才對
I believe I deserve some recognition from this board.
你說什麼
I'm sorry?
沒錯
Yes.
- 我不懂 - 哪堣懂
- I don't understand... - Which part?
你憑什麼值得認可
You deserve recognition?
我發現了你們安全系統中許多嚴重的漏洞
I believe, I pointed out some pretty gaping holes on your system...
- 能打斷一下嗎 - 可以
- Excuse me, May I? - Yes
扎克伯格先生 我負責哈佛所有電腦的網絡安全
Mr. Zuckerberg. I'm in charge of security for all computer on the Harvard network.
我可以向你保證網絡的高端性能
And I can assure you of its sophistication.
正是因為它優異的性能 我們在4個小時內就找到了你
In fact it was that level of sophistification that led us to you in for less than 4 hours.
- 4個小時 - 沒錯
- Four hours? - Yes, sir.
如果你沒發現我寫在寢室窗戶上的東西
That would be impressive except if you had know what you lookin' for,
那還算挺快的
You would've seen it written on my dorm room window.
- 那結果是 - 留校察看六個月
- So? - Six month academic probation.
- 他們是想殺雞儆猴 - 他們查了我的博客
- Well, they making an example out of you. - They have my blog.
真不該寫家畜那些東西的 真傻
I shouldn't have write nothing about the farm animals. That was stupid.
不過我不就開個玩笑麼 現在的人怎麼一點幽默感都沒有
But, I was kidding, for god sake. Doesn't anybody have some sense of humour?
當時告訴你停下的
But I tried to stop you.
我知道
***
你怎麼做的 讓所有女生都討厭我們了
How do you do these thing, How you manage to get all girls to hate us.
- 我當時怎麼就沒管住你 - 我知道
- Why do I let you... - I know.
- 你不能那麼做 - 愛德華多 夠了
- Can't do that... - Eduardo, I said enough.
讓我們看一個例子
Ok, let's look at a sample problem...
假設我們有一台電腦 16比特的虛擬地址 256字節的頁面大小
Suppose we're given a computer with a 16-bit virtual address and a page size of 256 bytes.
系統使用單級分頁 列表起始地址是0x400
The system uses one-level page tables, which start at address 0x400.
可能16位系統有直接內存訪問功能 無所謂 （你個混蛋）
Maybe you want to have DMA on your 16-bit system, who knows?
前幾個頁面文件用於保存硬體標識等信息
The first few pages are reserved for hardware flags, etc.
假定分頁表頭有八個狀態位
Assume page table entries have eight status bits.
這八個狀態位是…有人知道嗎？
The eight status bits would then be... Anybody?
我看到第一個退出的人了
And I see we have our first surrender.
沒關係 扎克伯格先生 很多比你聰明的人也過不了這課
Don't worry, Mr. Zuckerberg, brighter men than you have tried and failed at this class.
一個有效位 一個修改位 一個參考位  五個允許位
One valid bit, 1 modify bit, 1 reference bit and 5 permission bits.
答對了
That is correct.
有人知道他怎麼算的嗎
***
馬克
Mark?
你是馬克·扎克伯格嗎？
Are you Mark Zuckerberg?
是我
Yeah.
- 我是卡梅隆·溫克艾沃斯 - 你好
- Cameron Winklevoss. - Hi...
泰勒·溫克艾沃斯
Tyler Winklevoss.
你倆有什麼關係嗎
Are you guys related?
- 不錯 - 真有趣
- It's good. - Funny.
第一次有人這麼問
We never heard that before.
找我有什麼事 我冒犯你們的女朋友了嗎
So what can I do for you? Did I insult your girlfriends?
不 沒有 說實話 我還真不知道
No, we didn't, Actually... I don't know.
- 我們還沒問過 - 或許是該問問了
- We never asked. - Maybe we should do that...
我們有個想法想和你談談
** We have an idea we want to talk you about.
有時間嗎？
Do you have a minute?
你們看起來好像經常去健身
You guys look like you spend some time at a gym.
- 沒辦法 - 為什麼
- We have to. - ***
我們是賽艇隊的
We row crew.
- 那我應該有時間了 - 很好
- Yeah, I've got a minute. - ***
- 你去過坡斯廉俱樂部嗎？ - 沒
- So you ever been in The Porcellian? - No
好吧 那我們就在這吧 不是會員的話進不去的
Allright we gonna stay, we can't take you past the bike room 'cause you're not a member.
我聽說了
I've heard.
來點三明治什麼的嗎
Wanna sandwich or something?
好的
ok.
- 你就是馬克 - 對
- Mark, right? - yeah.
- 馬克 這是迪維亞·納蘭德亞 我們的搭檔 - 你好
- Mark, this is Divya Narendra, our partner. - Hi.
你的Facemash讓我們印象深刻
We were really impressed with facemash.
我們查了下 你還創建了CourseMatch
And then we checked you out and you also built CourseMatch.
我不知道什麼CourseMatch
I don't know CourseMatch.
你可以上網查朋友都選了哪些課
You go online and you see what courses your friend are taking is...
你真是厲害啊
You are really smart, man.
- 馬克 - 怎麼了？
- Mark... - Yeah.
我們剛才正說著CourseMatch呢
***
小兒科而已
********
你高中就做過什麼 對吧？
And you invented something in high school too, right?
一個MP3的應用程序 能自動識別使用者的品味
An app for an MP3 player that recognizes your taste in music.
有人想買嗎？
Anybody try to buy it?
微軟
Microsoft.
你賣了多少？
How much?
我沒賣它 我作為免費軟體傳到網上了
I didn't sell it. I uploaded for free.
- 免費？ - 沒錯
- For free? - Yeah.
為什麼？
Why?
好吧 我們最近在忙一個創意 我們覺得很不錯
Ok, well. We have something that we've been working for a while. We think it's great.
名字是"哈佛關係網"
It's called HarvardConnection.
你可以創建自己的主頁 興趣 簡介 朋友 照片…
You create your own page. Interests, bio, friends, pics.
別人就能從網上找到你 發送請求
***
這跟MySpace或Freindster有什麼區別嗎
Yeah, how this different from MySpace or Friendster?
harvard.edu
Harvard-dot-E-D-U.
harvard.edu是全國最具聲望的郵箱服務器
Harvard.edu is the most prestigious e-mail address in the country.
這些理念主要是基於與女生的交往…
And the whole site kinda base on the idea with girls...
- 不想惹上麻煩 但是… - 女孩都想跟哈佛男約會
- Not to putting anything in delicate. - Girls wanna go with guys who go to Harvard.
我和我哥就不用擔心惹上麻煩
***
它和我們剛才談論的Myspace和Friendster
Many different between what we're talkin' about
以及其它社交網絡最重要的區別就在於
and MySpace or Friendster any others social networks inside...
它是獨一無二的
is that exclusivity...
對嗎
Right?
沒錯
Right.
馬克 我們期待與你合作
Yeah, we'd love you to work with this Mark.
我們需要像你這樣有創造力的程序員
We need a gifted programmer and you're creative.
我們知道你會認真考慮的
And we know you would take this serious...
女權組織已經準備向你宣戰了
Womens group already declare a war...
這可以幫你恢復形象
You know, this could help rehabilitate you image.
你們為什麼幫我
Wow, you would do that for me?
我們希望與你合作
We'd like to work with you.
我們的第一個程序員畢業了 去了Google
Our first programmer graduated and went to work at Google.
第二個是個學術帝 整天寫作業
Our second programmer just got overwhelmed with school work.
我們需要你建立網站 編寫代碼 我們會提供…
We will need you to build the site, write the code and we'll provide...
我干了
I'm in...
- 什麼？ - 我加入了
- What? - I'm in.
太棒了
Awesome!
你當時就那麼說的嗎
That's what you said?
都三四年前的事了 記不清了
It was 3 or 4 years ago... I don't know what I said.
你什麼時候去找的愛德華多
When did you come Eduardo?
我不明白這個問題
I don't understand the question.
你記得你答應他們了嗎
Do you remember answering an affirmative?
答應？
The affirmative...
你什麼時候告訴愛德華多Facebook的想法的
When did you come to Eduardo with the idea for facebook?
那時候還叫The Facebook
It was called the facebook then.
這不是重點
It doesn't need to be that difficult.
我要同時應付兩起訴訟
I'm currently in the middle of 2 differents law suits.
你答應他們了嗎
Did you answer affirmatively,
當泰勒和卡梅隆在十一月請你建立Harvard Connection時
When Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss, Divya Narendra ask you to build Harvard Connection,
你同意了嗎
Did you say, yes?
我說 我會幫忙的
I said I'd help.
你什麼時候去找薩法倫 把Facebook的想法告訴他的
When did you approached Mr. Saverin with the idea for the facebook?
可不是我找的他
I wouldn't say I approached him.
塞？
Sy?
你可以回答這個問題
You can answer the question.
在一個叫阿爾法艾普西隆圓周率的派對上
At a party at Alpha Epsilon Pi
那是什麼
What's that?
一個猶太聯誼會
The jewish fraternity.
加勒比海之夜
It was Caribbean night.
雖然我們這種人對亞洲女孩沒什麼吸引力
It's not that guys like me are generally attracted to Asian girls.
但我們卻迷上了亞洲女孩
It's that Asian girls are generally attracted to guys like me.
我在研究一種算法 確定猶太人和亞洲姑娘的關係
I'm developing an algorithm to define the connection between Jewish guys and Asian girls.
這並不複雜 他們身材性感 頭腦聰明
I don't think it's that complicated. They're hot, They're smart,
不是猶太人 又不會跳舞
they're not Jewish and they can't dance.
- 馬克來了 - 馬克
- Hey, Mark's here. - Mark.
失陪下
***
我想到個點子
I think I've come up with something.
等等 我和你說個不可思議的事
Hang on, I've gotta tell you something you're not going to believe.
- 什麼事 - 鳳凰俱樂部邀請我了
- What? - I got punched by the Phoenix.
- 開玩笑吧 - 真的
- Are You kidding? - No.
只是四步程序的第一步
I mean it's just the first of the 4 step process,
他們週一把邀請函塞到我門縫
But they slipped the invitation under my door tonight.
明天我就要第一次參加派對了
I go to the first punch party tomorrow.
鳳凰俱樂部邀請你了？
You got punch by The Phoenix.
沒錯 它可能真是個多元化的俱樂部
Yeah, probably, it was just a diversity thing.
沒錯 就是 我還會這樣特立獨行下去
It was just a diversity thing. I'll just ride that horse until...
你要跟我說什麼來著
What did you want to talk about?
- 馬克 - 怎麼
- Mark? - Yeah.
你說你找我有事
You said you've come up with something.
沒錯 出來說
Yeah, I think I've come up with something. Come outside.
外面才20度
It's 20 degrees outside.
我受不了那個尼亞加拉大瀑布 它和加勒比海有什麼關係啊
I can't stare to that loop of Niagara falls which has absolutely nothing to do with the Caribbean.
人們會爭著上Facemash的對吧
People came to Facemash in a stampede, right?
沒錯
Yeah.
但這並不是因為他們想看美女
But it wasn't because the saw pictures of hot girls.
因為在網上美女的照片到處都是
You can go any around on the internet and see pictures of hot girls.
沒錯
Yeah.
這是因為他們能看到認識女生的照片
That was because they saw pictures of girls that they knew.
大家想上網看看他們的朋友
People wanna go on the internet and check out their friends,
為什麼我們不創建這樣一個網站呢
So why not build the website that offers that?
你可以隨意瀏覽朋友照片 簡介之類的信息
Friends, pictures, profiles, whatever you can visit, browse around.
甚至能訪問你在派對剛認識的女孩 我說的不是那種交友網站
Maybe its someone you just met at a party. But I'm not talkin' about a dating site.
我指的是 將整個大學的社交網絡弄到網上去
I'm talkin' about taking the entire social experience of college and putting it online.
我腿沒感覺了
I can't feel my legs
這太讓人興奮了 愛德華多
I know, I'm totally psyched about this. But Wardo...
- 好 - 它是獨一無二的
- Yeah... - It would be exclusive.
你必須認識網上那個人 才會同意他訪問你的頁面
You would've to know the people on the site to get pass thru on page.
- 就像收到邀請一樣 - 不錯
- Like getting punched. - That's good
這就像終極俱樂部一樣 不同的是我們是主席
Wardo, it's like a Final Clubs except we're the president.
我跟他說了 這是個好主意
I told him i thought it sounded great.
這是個偉大的想法
It was a great idea.
用不著去偷
There's nothing to hack.
人們會上傳自己的照片 填寫自己的資料
People were gonna provide their own pictures, their own information.
還可以選擇否邀請自己的好友加入這個網絡
And people had the ability to invite or not invite their friends to join.
就像一個完全由社會網絡構成的東西
See, in the world were the social structure was everything.
它就是那樣一個東西
That was the "THING".
這是個大工程
It was a big project.
他要為此編寫成千上萬行代碼
And he was going to have to write ten of thousands of lines of code.
我當時還想 為什麼是他 而不是他室友來找我
So I wonder, why he was coming to me and not to his room mate.
達斯汀·摩斯克維茨 和克奡窗P休斯都是程序員
Dustin Moskowitz and Chris Hughes they're programmers.
我們當時需要一點資金 租個服務器傳到網上去
We're gonna need a little start-up cash to rent the servers and get it online.
那就是原因
So that was why.
- 他提條件了嗎 - 當然
- Did he offers terms? - Yes.
我們分成 三七開
We'll split it. 70-30
我拿七成 你拿三成 你負責投資上千的美金
Seventy for me, Thirty for you for you, putting up a thousands dollar.
還有處理一切生意上的事情 你做首席財務官
And for handling everything on the business end. You're CFO
- 你怎麼說 - 我說 大展身手吧
- And you said? - I said "Let's do it"
- 好的 他還說了什麼沒有 - 有
- Ok, did he add anything else? - Yes.
也許是個多元的俱樂部
It probably was a diversity thing
但又如何呢
but so what?
你覺得他為什麼要這麼說
Why do you think he said that?
格雷琴 抱歉打斷你 但這又是誰的發現呢
Gretchen, excuse me for interrupting, But whose discovery it is?
- 塞 如果你讓我繼續問下去的話… - 你又想暗示什麼
- Sy, if you let me continue with my line of question... - What do you suggesting?
他們在暗示我嫉妒愛德華多 被鳳凰俱樂部邀請了
They're suggesting I was jealous of Eduardo for getting punched by Phoenix.
於是決定設計把他排擠出 一個我還沒設立的公司
and began a plan to screw him out of the company I haven't even invented yet.
- 不是嗎 - 格雷琴…
- Were you? - Gretchen...
我嫉妒愛德華多？
Jealous of Eduardo?
哦 別記下來 這話不用記錄
Oh, stop typing, we're off the record.
女士 我知道你好好調查了一番
Maam, I know you've done your home work.
所以說你肯定知道錢並非是我生活的重心
And so you know that money isn't a big part of my life,
但現在我可以買下整條奧本大街
But at the moment I could buy I could buy Mt. Auburn Street,
買下鳳凰俱樂部 再把它變成我的乒乓室
Take the Phoenix Club and turn it into my pingpong room.
回頭告訴你派對的情況
I'll let you know how the party is,
我們發現您在涉及Facebook的案件中 一起是原告 一起是證人
We recognize that you're a plaintiff in one suit involving Facebook and a witness in another.
- 是的 先生 - 在馬克告訴你他的想法
- Yes, Sir. - At any time In the weeks,
之前的幾周內
prior to Mark telling you his idea,
他有沒有提起過泰勒和卡梅隆·溫克艾沃斯 迪維亞·納蘭德拉或者是"哈佛關係網"？
Did he mention Tyler Winklevoss, Cameron Winklevoss, Divya Narendra or HarvardConnection?
有 他說他們邀請他去建設他們的網站
Yes. He said they'd asked him to work on their site.
但是他一看到他們的成果後 就覺得不值得他花時間去做
But that he'd looked at what they had and decided it wasn't worth his time.
他說哪怕是他最爛的朋友都比這些人要懂得如何使一個網站吸引人
He said even his most pathetic friends knew more about getting people interested in a website than these guys.
"這些人" 指的是我的客戶們
"These guys" meaning my clients.
對 他很討厭 馬克很討厭他們 就是你的客戶們
Yes. He resented, Mark resented that they, that your clients,
覺得他在經歷了Facemash事件後 需要恢復形象
thought that he need to rehabilitate his image after the Facemash thing
但其實馬克什麼都不想恢復
but Mark didn't want to rehabilitate anything.
他用Facemash黑了哈佛的電腦系統 進入了董事會的系統內
With Facemash he'd hack into Harvard computers, he dumps his nose to the Ad Board.
聲譽滿載 Facemash成就了 他夢寐以求的一切
He got a lot of honorarity. Facemash did exactly what he wanted it to do.
您是否知道 在建設Facebook的同時
Were you aware that while Mr. Zuckerberg was building the Facebook,
扎克伯格先生在同原告接觸？
He was also communicating with the plaintiffs?
那時候我還不知道 但是…
Not at the time I wasn't. But...
我知道他沒有忙著搞 溫克艾沃斯兄弟的交友網站
It really didn't have much to do with The Winkelvoss dating site.
你怎麼知道的 你都沒有…
How would you know? You' weren't even...
您是否知道 扎克伯格先生 在建設Facebook的同時
Were you aware that while Mr. Zuckerberg was building TheFacebook,
他誤導原告使之相信 他是在建設"哈佛關係網"？
He was leading the plaintiffs to believe he was building HarvardConnection?
你這是沒有證據 臆推結論
You're offering a conclusion not found an evidence.
現在我就給你看證據…
We are about to finding an evidence...
這封是馬克·扎克伯格於2003年11月30日發給泰勒·溫克艾沃斯的郵件
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler Winklevoss November 30, 2003
"我讀了你們發給我的關於重建 哈佛關係網的資料
I read over all the stuff you sent me re-HarvardConnection,
看上去不需要花很多時間就能完成了
and it seems like it shouldn't take too long to implement,
等我明晚準備好所有基礎設備 我們再仔細談談"
so we can talk about it after I get all the basic functionality up tomorrow night.
這封是馬克·扎克伯格於03年12月1日發給卡梅隆·溫克艾沃斯的郵件
From Mark Zuckerberg to Cameron Winklevoss. December 1, 2003.
"抱歉昨晚打不通我的電話 我剛看到三個你打來的未接來電
"Sorry I was unreachable tonight. I just got about three of your missed calls.
我在做系統課留的作業"
I was working on a problem set for my sytems class"
這封是馬克·扎克伯格於03年12月10日發給卡梅隆及泰勒·溫克艾沃斯的郵件
Mark Zuckerberg to Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss. December 10, 2003.
"這個禮拜我一直忙於上課和做作業
"This week has been pretty busy thus far with classes and work"
所以我覺得還是推遲會面吧"
"So I think it's probably best to postpone the meeting."
"明天我也很忙"
"I'm also really busy tomorrow"
好吧 大夥兒有沒有覺得這傢伙有點奇怪？
***
告訴他可以 但是我們必須 在休假前碰一次面
Tell him okay but we do have to make sure that we meet up before we all head off for break.
我知道 我知道 好的 回見
***
- 嗨 馬克 - 嗨
- Hi Mark, - Hi,
我需要一台Linux專用的主機來運作Apache系統 後台要MySQL的
I need a dedicated Linux box running Apache with a mySQL back-end.
這要花多點小錢
It's gonna cost a little more money.
- 大概要多多少？ - 大概要多200
- How much more? - About 200 more.
- 必須得買嗎 - 必須搞定流量問題
- Do we need it? - Gotta handle the traffic.
- 那買吧 - 我已經買好了
- Do it. - I already did.
嘿 你猜怎麼著
Hey guess what...
我進了第二輪了
I'm in the 2nd cut.
很好啊 你該自豪了
That's good. You should be proud of that right there,
要是沒晉級千萬別難過
Don't worry if you don't make it any further.
我這就走
I'll get out of here.
這封是馬克·扎克伯格於2003年12月10日發給卡梅隆及泰勒·溫克艾沃斯
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss and Divya Narendra.
還有迪維亞·納蘭德拉的郵件
December 15, 2003.
我有個代碼段出了問題 我這才著手解決
I have a cs problem set that I'm just getting started with,
大概要編15個小時的程 所以明晚我很忙
And It should be about 15 hours of coding so I'll be busy tomorrow night,
要到下個禮拜三下午我才有空會面
I won't really be free to meet until next Wednesday afternoon.
禮拜三下午我也不能來了
I have to cancel Wednesday afternoon.
這段時間我一直混在實驗室 而且…
I've basically been in the lab this whole time and also...
禮拜六也不行 我要去見我爹娘
Won't be able to do it Saturday as I have to meet up with my parents...
石板上寫著 這位是約翰·哈佛 他於1638年創建了哈佛大學
As the plaque reads, this is John Harvard, founder of Harvard University in 1638.
這也被稱為三大謊言雕像
It's also called The Statue of Three Lies.
那三大謊言是什麼呢
What are the three lies?
道得先生
Mr. Dowd.
三大謊言
The three lies,
一…該死
First... Shit!
- 把褲子脫了 - 我早知道
- Take your pants off. - I know.
薩佛林先生
Mr. Saverin.
一 哈佛於1636年創建 而非1638
1) Harvard was founded in 1636 not 1638.
二 哈佛的創始人並非約翰·哈佛
2) Harvard was not founded by John Harvard
還有 這不是約翰·哈佛的雕像
and 3) That's not John Harvard.
那他又是誰？
Who is it?
雕…雕塑家的好友 丹尼爾…切斯特
F-friend of the sculptor, Daniel... Chester.
把外套穿上吧
Keep you jacket on.
繼與我客戶們的首次見面的39天之後
39 days after Mr. Zuckerberg's initial meeting with my clients
扎克伯格先生依然沒有完成 建設"哈佛關係網"的工作
And he still hadn't completed work on HarvardConnection.
但是在2004年1月11日
But On January 11, 2004
扎克伯格先生在Network Solution上註冊了Facebook的域名
Mr. Zuckerberg registered the domain name the facebook by Network Solution.
請問您是否知道 他到底有沒有 著手建設"哈佛關係網"？
To the best of your knowledge, had he even begun work on HarvardConnection?
據我所知 沒有
Not to my knowledge. No.
嗨 卡梅隆 "我依然懷疑 我們網站的功能夠不夠吸引
Hi Cameroon, "I'm still a little skeptical that we have enough functionality in the site to really draw the attention
並獲得維繫網站的評論關注"
And gain the critical mass necessary to get a site like this to run"
我們來日再談？
We'll speak soon?
這是否為第一次他提出困難？
This is the first time he mentioned any problem?
是的
Yes, he was
你們共給扎克伯格先生發了36封電郵 收到了16封回復
You'd sent 36 e-mails to Mr. Zuckerberg and received 16 e-mails in return,
而這是第一次他提到自己不太樂意
And this was the first time he indicated that he's not happy.
沒錯
That's correct!
他花了42天來研究我們的系統 然後捷足先登
He had 42 days to study our system and get out ahead...
你看到Facebook上有一條你的代碼嗎
Do you see any of your code on Facebook?
- 塞 - 我用了你們的代碼嗎
- *** - Did I use any of your code?
你偷的他媽的是我們整個創意
You stole our whole god damn idea.
夥計們
Fellas,
- 哈佛人上的交友網站啊 - 我能繼續讀證據材料嗎
- What a match-dot-com for Harvard guys! - Can I continue with my deposition
你們真的不必請一個鑒證組來調查
You know you really don't need a forensic team to get to bottom of this
如果你們覺得自己是Facebook的創建者 你們得創造出一個Facebook來
If you guys were the inventors of Facebook you'd have invented Facebook.
我真等不及踩扁你 等你賠償了
I can't wait to stand over your shoulder while you write us a check.
才怪
No Shit.
繼續吧
Let's continue.
2004年2月4日
February 4, 2004
馬克… 馬克…
Mark... Mark...
你藝術史課上有個女生 叫斯蒂芬妮·艾提絲
There is a girl in your art history class name Stephanie Attis.
你知不知道她有沒有男朋友啊
Do you happen to know if she has a boyfriend?
你有沒有看到過她跟別人在一起？
Have you ever seen her with anyone.
要是沒有的話 你知不知道 她想不想找一個男朋友？
And if not, do you happen to know if she's looking to go out with anyone?
人們又不在胸口掛牌 告訴別人…
People don't walk around with a sign on them that says some...
馬克？
***
我們該9點碰頭的
We were supposed to meet at 9
- 你有睡過覺麼 - 我要加點東西上去
- Have you slept yet? - I've to add something.
什麼
What?
哇 這看上去不錯 這看上去真的不錯
Shit that's look good, That's look really good.
簡單了當 不花哨
It's clean and simple, no disneyland...
但是看著
But watch...
你寫了什麼
What'd you write?
感情狀態 對某人感興趣
Relationship status, Interested in,
這就是大學生活的動力所在 你是否在與人上床
This is what drives live in college. Are you having sex or aren't you
有的人上某些課 只是為了坐在那個位置上
It's why people take certain classes. And sit where they sit.
做他們所做的事情 這才是重點 你懂的
And do what they do, and it's um, centre, you know,
Facebook就是要做這樣的事情
That what's thefacebook is gonna be about...
大家來登錄
People gonna log on...
除了那些好看的噱頭 這媮晱]含著潛在實際的
Because after all the cake and watermelon, there's a chance they're actually gonna...
- 上床機會… - 泡個妞 對
- Get laid... - Meet a girl. Yes.
- 真的很棒 - 好了
- This is really good. - And that's it.
什麼意思
What d'you mean?
- 準備好了 - 準備好了？
- It's ready. - It's ready?
- 對 - 現在就好了？
- yeah. - right now?
現在就好了 這個是刊頭
That was it, and here's the masthead.
- 你還做了個刊頭 - 對
- You made a masthead. - Yeah.
- 愛德華多·薩佛林 聯名創始者 首席財務官 - 對
- Eduardo Saverin, Co-Founder and CFO. - yeah.
你不知道這對我父親來說意味著什麼
You have no idea how what that's gonna mean for my father.
我當然知道
Sure I do...
什麼時候上線？
When's it go on live?
現在 拿出你的筆記本
Right now, take your laptop out.
為什麼要我的筆記本
Why we do need my laptop.
因為你要給鳳凰俱樂部的成員 每人發一封郵件
Because you've got e-mails for everybody at Phoenix.
對 我不知道…
yeah.I'm not sure ...
要是我給他們發垃圾電郵的話 他們也不會生什麼氣…
it's gonna be cool with them that I spam their...
- 這不是垃圾電郵 - 我知道不是
- It's not spam. - I know it's not spam
要是我們只給自己的朋友發 這東西只能在電腦實驗室堶捷Ф膜F
If we send it to our friends it'll just bounce around the computer lab.
我還沒入選呢
I haven't gotten in yet.
這些人有人脈 我需要他們的電郵
These guys know people and I need their e-mails.
- 好吧 - 很好
- Sure - Good.
- 把電郵地址給我 - jabberwock12@harvard.edu
- Give me the mailing list. - jabberwock12@harvard E-D-U.
這些人 成了文學天才…
These guys.
就因為他們有著世界上最清晰的 劉易斯卡洛爾註解本
They're literary geniuses 'cause the world's most obvious Lewis Caroll reference is in their...
他們也沒這麼差勁啦
They're not so bad
- 我就說說 - 對 你沒說錯
- I'm just saying. - Yeah, you're right.
網站上線了
The site's live.
我們去喝一杯慶祝下
You know, Let's go get a drink and celebrate.
我請客
I'm buying.
馬克
Mark,
馬克 你是在祈禱嗎
Mark, are you praying?
科爾·波特和歐文·柏林有什麼事跡？ (音樂家)
What ever happened to Cole Porter and Irving Berlin?
這是情人節主題 他們在演唱情歌
It's a Valentine's theme. They playing love songs.
很好 科爾·波特和歐文·柏林 從沒有寫過情歌
Good point, 'cause Cole Porter and Irving Berlin never wrote any love songs.
親愛的 別老看著電腦了
Honey, just put your laptop away...
74個人給我電郵了同一個鏈接
Seventy four people spam me the same link.
凱西…
Casey...
- 是什麼鏈接 - 不知道
- What is it? - I don't know
希望是一張像希特勒的貓咪圖片 那可是百看不厭的
But I'm really hoping it's cat look like a hitler 'cause i can never get enough of that.
哦 不是
No, it's not.
迪夫？
Div?
怎麼了？
What?
迪夫 出什麼事了
Div, w-what is wrong?
- 嘿! - 現在別打擾!
- Hey! - Not now!
- 還要20分鐘 - 好吧
- We need 20 mins. - Ok.
我只是來告訴你們 扎克伯格偷了我們的網站
I just want to let you know that Zuckerberg stole our website.
- 馬克·扎克伯格？ - 他偷了我們的網站
- Mark Zuckerberg? - He stole our website.
已經上線超過36個小時了
It's been alive for more than 36 hours.
霍奇基斯先生
Mr. Hotchkiss
泰 爸爸跟律師都在線上了
Ty, the lawyer's on the phone with dad.
是的 先生 我和我弟弟泰勒在一起 還有我們的生意夥伴 迪維亞
Yes, Sir. I'm here with my brother Tyler, our business partner, Divya.
歡迎來到Facebook
Welcome to theFacebook.
Facebook是一部在線指南 將不同社交網絡的人聯繫在一起
theFacebook is an online directory that connects people through different social networks.
必須有Harvard.edu的郵箱才能註冊
You must have a Harvard.edu address to register.
沒錯 是的 先生
That's right. Yes, Sir.
我早些時候打過電話 我找馬克·扎克伯格
I called earlier, I'm looking for Mark Zuckerberg
是的 先生 他有幾句話被引述了 我可以讀給你聽
Yes, Sir. He's quoted a couple of times. I can read it to you.
"大家都在談論哈佛內部通行的校友冊"
"Everyone's been talking a lot about a universal facebook within Harvard"
"他"就是馬克
***
"我覺得大學這麼多年 還沒搞出來是挺傻的"
I think it's kind of silly that it would take the University a couple of years to get around to it.
"我做得這麼精妙 而他們不行 而且我只用了一個禮拜的時間"
I can do it in class jobs than they can't and I did it in a week.
- 告訴他 迪維亞·納蘭德拉打電話來過 感激不盡 - 這就是我們說的
- Tell him, Divya Narendra called, I appreciate it. - That's how we talks.
到昨天晚上為止 已經有650名學生註冊了扎克伯格的Facebook.com
As of yesterday evening, Zuckerberg set over 650 students to registered thefacebook.com
他說 預計今天早上為止 會有900名學生註冊
He said that he anticipated 900 students would've join the site by this morning.
迪維亞剛剛讀到第一天 已經有650名學生註冊了
Divya was just reading that 650 students signed up on the first day
要是我是個毒販子 一天也能向650個人派免費毒品
If I was I drug dealer I could give free drugs to 650 people in one day.
- 這人連三個朋友都沒有… - 夥計們 拜託了 安靜點
- This guy doesn't have 3 friends to rob... - Guys, please, come on...
好的 我們會辦到的 霍奇基斯先生 我們整理好資料 然後電郵給你
Alright that's what we'll do, Mr. Hotchkiss ** Then we e-mail it to you.
你自己上不了那個網站
You won't be able to get on the website yourself.
因為你沒有哈佛的 呃
Because you don't have a harvard... uhm..
還是我們電郵給你比較方便
you know what it would be easy for us to e-mail it to you.
我相信你說的沒錯 他是個好人
I'm sure you right... He's a good guy,
他很聰明 我知道 他並非故意…這麼做的
And he's very bright and I'm sure he didn't mean to... do what he did.
好的 非常感謝
Alright, thank you very much...
爸爸 我們也愛你
And Dad, Love you too.
他是個好人？
He good guy?
我們不知道他是不是個壞人
We don't know that he's not a good guy.
我們知道他偷了我們的想法
We know he Stole our idea
我們知道他當著我們的面 騙了我們一個半月
We know that he lied to our faces for a month and half
他從沒當著我們的面
He never lie to our face
他是從見著我們的面 但他用郵件扯謊了
He never saw our faces! Fine, he lied to our e-mail accounts.
然後領先了我們42天
So he got himself 42-days head start
因為他知道的你不知道 那就是先發制人才有勝算
He knows what apparently you don't which is that getting there first is everything.
我有的是競爭意識 迪夫
I'm a competitive racer, Div,
你沒必要對我嘮叨 搶佔先機的重要性 謝謝
I don't think you need to school me on the importance of getting there first. Thank you.
好吧 剛那是你爸的律師？
Alright, that's was your father's lawyer?
對 是他的法律顧問
Yeah, well his in-house counsel.
他會來查看資料 如果覺得合適的話 他去函要求他罷手
He's gonna look at all this if he thinks it's appropriate he'll send a cease and desist letter.
這有什麼用
***
這麼 你還想要請一位 知識產權律師來起訴他麼
What, do you wanna hire an IP lawyer and sue him?
不 我想請黑幫用錘子好好地揍他一頓
No, I wanna hire the Sopranos to beat the shit out of him with a hammer!
- 我們不必這麼做 - 沒錯
- We don't have to do that. - That's right.
我們可以自己下手
We can do that ourself.
- 我6尺5寸 220磅 而且我們還是兩個人 - 我同意他的觀點
I'm six-five, 220lbs, and there's two of me. I'm with this guy.
好吧 我只能說我們得冷靜一下 再來看看該怎麼處理
Whatever, I'm saying let's calm down until we know what we're talking about.
你還要等多少資料
how much more information are you waiting for.
我們見過馬克三次 互發了52封電郵 我們可以證明他偷看了我們的代碼
We met with Mark 3 times, exchanged 52 e-mails, we can prove that he looked at the code...
這頁面下面寫的什麼
what is that on the bottom of page
寫著"馬克·扎克伯格出品"
It's "A Mark Zuckerberg production"
- 主頁上嗎 - 每一頁都有
- On the homepage? - On every pages.
該死 幹得太漂亮了
Shit. I need to let the classiness waft over me.
好吧 聽著
Ok, look...
上面寫著"扎克伯格說希望 這些保密性的選擇
They wrote, "Zuckerberg said that he hoped the privacy options...
能為他挽回聲譽 Facemash.com的事情他犯了眾怒"
...would help to restore his reputation following student outrage over Facemash.com"
這正是我們對他說的話 他這是挑釁我們
That's exactly what we said to him. He's giving us "the finger" in the Crimson
我們這麼乾坐著等老爸的律師來處理 我們至少該寫點什麼反駁…
While we're waiting for dad's lawyer to look this stuff over, we can at least...
- 不 - 讓大家知道…
- No... - ***
這沒什麼好爭的!
***
我們不能跟他打筆仗 也不能起訴他
We're not starting a knife fight in the Crimson and we're not suing anybody.
為什麼
Why not?
我不明白 為什麼不能
***
他會說我蠢的
He's gonna say it's stupid.
什麼 誰 我嗎
What, who? Me?
說呀 為什麼不
Say it why not?
因為我們是哈佛的紳士
Because we're gentlemen of Harvard.
這堿O哈佛 不能說別人壞話 也不能起訴別人
This is Harvard. Where you don't plant stories and you don't sue people.
你覺得就他會說你蠢嗎
You thought he was going to be the only one who thought that was stupid?
當時你說自己有這個想法
During the time when you say you had this idea,
你是否知道泰勒和卡梅隆出身名門？
Did you know Tyler and Cameron came from a family of means?
名門？
A family of means?
你是否知道他們的父親很有錢
Did you know that his father was wealthy.
我不知道你為什麼要問我這個
I'm not sure why you're asking me that.
這不重要 你肯定知道我為什麼要問你
It's not important that you be sure why I'm asking you.
對你是不重要
It's not important to you.
塞…
Sy...
你知不知道他們家很有錢
Did you know that they came from money?
我不知道他們家有沒有錢
I had no idea whether they came from money or not.
在一封你給納蘭德拉先生的電郵 你提到了一家叫泰特·溫克艾沃斯的投資顧問公司
In one of your e-mails to Mr. Narendra you reference Tate Winklevoss consulting firm.
你說有就有了
If you say so.
霍華德·溫克艾沃斯創建了這家公司 市值上億
Howard Winklevoss founded the firm and its assets are in the hundreds of millions.
你還知道泰勒及卡梅隆是 哈佛終極俱樂部坡斯廉的成員
You also knew that Tyler and Cameron were members of a Harvard Final club called the Porcellian.
- 他們對我說過了 - 抱歉我們邀請你了
- They pointed that out? - Excuse us for inviting you in.
請我去停車庫
To the bike room...
所以說 可以認為 你是知道我的客戶們很有錢了
So it's safe to say you were aware that my clients had money?
- 是的 - 我來告訴你為什麼要這麼問
- Yes. - Let me tell you why I'm asking.
我在想
I'm wondering why...
當你的互聯網生意需要1000美金投資時 你為什麼沒有問我的客戶們要
If you needed a $1000 for an internet venture you didn't ask my clients for it.
他們會告訴你其中的利弊…
They'd demonstrated to you an interest in this kind of thing...
我去問我的朋友要錢投資是因為我想讓他成為我的合夥人
I went to my friend for the money because that he's who I wanted to be partners with...
愛德華多是哈佛投資者協會的主席 同時也是我的摯交好友
Eduardo was presidents of the Harvard Inverstors Association and he was also my best friend.
你的摯交好友正起訴你 問你要6億美金呢
Your best friend is suing you for 600 million dollars.
我不知道 你來告訴我吧
I didn't know that. tell me more!
愛德華多 首次發佈之後情況如何
Eduardo, what happen after the initial lunch?
塞 能否稱呼我的客戶為薩佛林先生
Sy would you mind addressing as Mr. Saverin
- 格雷琴 他們是摯交好友 - 不再是了
- Gretchen, they're best friend - Not anymore
我之前就已經…
I already went through this on the...
算了 薩佛林先生…
Nevermind, Mr. Saverin...
首次發佈之後情況如何
***
簡直就和爆炸一樣 校園堜狾酗H都在用
It's exploded, everybody on campus was using it
兩個禮拜之後 大家見面就說 "上Facebook加我"
"Facebook-me" was the common expression after two weeks.
而馬克呢
and Mark...
馬克成了校園堻怜{亮的人物 一舉擊敗了19位諾貝爾獲獎者
And Mark was biggest thing on a campus that included 19 Nobel Laureates,
15位普利策獎獲得者 兩位未來的奧林匹克冠軍
15 Pulitzer Prize Winners, two future Olympians
和一位電影明星
and a movie star.
電影明星是誰
Who's the movie star?
有關係嗎
Does it matter?
沒有
No.
那天天氣很好 我去了位於拉德克利夫的宿舍
Beautiful day. And I was up in my Radcliffe dorm.
他帶了那本雜誌給我看
He brought that magazine up and he saw it to me
他說"看 再不動手就輪不到我們了"
And he said, "Look, it's gonna happen without us. We've got to start now."
我說 "好吧"
And I said... "Okay."
我們去買基礎硬體
Let's get basic hardware.
許多人都以為自己知道後續的事情 但其實並非如此
Most of you think you know the rest of story that you may not.
開始挺寒酸的
The beginning of the industry were very humble...
那台雜誌封面上的組裝機上 搭載的是8080處理器
That kit computer on the cover of that magazine, had an 8080 processor in it.
除非你再加錢買一個1K內存擴展板 不然的話只有256比特的儲存空間
Unless you paid extra for 1K memory board 256bits,
所以我們的挑戰並非是 運行一台4K比特的電腦
so the challenges *** but,
而是要留下運行程序的空間
****
你的朋友 是叫馬克·扎克伯格嗎
*** Isn't that Mark Zuckerberg?
對
Yeah
- 他創造了Facebook？ - 對
- He made facebook? - Yeah.
我是說我們倆創造了 對 我們… 對
I mean both of us. Yeah, we... yes.
酷 我叫克奡絡式P李 這位是愛麗絲
Cool. I'm Christy Lee. This is Alice.
嗨
hi.
很高興見到你們
Nice to meet you
回家後上Facebook加我 我們出去喝一杯
Facebook-me when you get home We can all go out and grab a drink.
當然了 我一定會的
Certainly, absolutely will do that.
她說"上Facebook加我" 還有我們出去喝一杯
She said "Facebook-me" and we can all go for a drink later.
有兩個理由 為什麼這句話太棒了
Which is stunningly great for two reasons.
首先 她說"上Facebook加我" 對麼？ 然後…
One she said "Facebook-me". Right? And the other...
- 她們想要出去喝杯 - 對
- They wanna have drinks later. - Yes
你有聽到過一句話 有這麼多好事兒嗎
Have you ever heard so many different good things packed into one regular-sized sentence?
抱歉 馬克？
Excuse me. Mark?
對
Yeah
我是斯圖爾特·辛格 我在你的操作系統實驗室
I'm Stuart Singer. I'm in your O.S. lab.
對
Sure.
- Facebook搞得真棒 - 太棒了
- Awesome job with theFacebook. - Awesome Job.
- 謝謝 - 我叫鮑勃
- Thanks. - I'm Bob.
- 你好 - 你知道 我發誓
- How are you doin'. - You know, I could swear..
他說這房間埵酗U一位比爾蓋茨 當時他就看著你
he was looking at you when he said The next Bill Gates could be right in this room.
不一定吧
I doubt it
我來晚了 我都不知道發言人是誰
I showed up late, I don't even know who the speaker was.
就是比爾蓋茨
It was Bill Gates.
該死 這就說得通了
Shit... that's make sense.
好吧 謝謝各位了
Alright, thanks guys.
你傻了還是你腦殘了？
Are you moron? Are you medically stupid?
比爾蓋茨在你眼前 晃了一個小時你都沒認出來？
You can't recognize Bill Gates in front of you for an hour?
現在馬克·扎克伯格會覺得我們是拿了殘奧會獎學金進的哈佛…
Mark Zuckerberg now thinks we got into Harvard on a dimwit scholarship.
我要去找把格洛克斃了你
I'm gonna get a Glock...
我們得把這東西套現了
It's time to monetize the thing.
他們是從哪兒來的
What are their natives?
- 你聽到我說的話了嗎 - 什麼話
- Did you heard what I just said? - When?
我說是時候把網站套現了
I said it's times to monetize the site
什麼意思
What is that mean?
意思說該讓網站開始盈利了
It means time for the website generating the revenue.
不 我知道那個詞什麼意思 我是問你要這麼做
No, I know what the word means. I'm asking how do you want to do it?
- 廣告 - 不
- Advertising. - No.
- 我們有4000個成員 - 因為Facebook很酷
- We've got 4000 members. - 'Cause theFacebook is cool.
要是我們開始彈百事的小廣告 那就不酷了
And if we start selling pop-ups for Mountain Dew it's not gonna be cool.
我倒是沒有想到百事廣告 不過…
Well I wasn't thinking it would be Mountain Dew but at some point,
既然是我要處理生意上的業務 那網站…
And I'm talkin' as the business end of the company, the site...
我們都不知道這到底什麼 我們不知道現在是什麼
We don't even know what it is yet, we don't what it is...
也不知道它會變成什麼
We don't know what it can be.
也不知道未來它會是什麼 我們只知道它很酷
We don't know what it will be. We know that it's cool,
這就是一個無價之寶 我不能放棄這點
That's a priceless asset and I'm not giving it up.
- 所以說不會玩完咯 - 不會玩完
- So it won't be finish? - It won't be finish.
這就是關鍵 時尚的東西永遠不會玩完
That's the point, the way fashion never finish
- 什麼 - 時尚 時尚永遠不會玩完
- What? - Fashion, fashion is never finish.
你在討論時尚 真的嗎 這是你嗎
You talkin' about fashion, really you?
我在說那個想法 我在說它不會玩完
I'm talkin' about the idea I'm sayin' that never finish
好吧 但他們至少用時尚賺錢了 賣賣褲子什麼的
Ok, but they manage to make money, sellin' pants
馬克 這是什麼
Mark what is this?
- 什麼什麼 - 這個
- What? - this.
這叫最後通牒 她們叫什麼來著
It's called the cease and desist letter. What were their names?
- 誰 - 剛剛的姑娘們
- Who? - The girls.
你什麼時候收到的
When did you get this?
大概10天前 就在我們發佈網站之後
About ten days ago. Right after we launched the site
我的天
***
嘿 那倆姑娘 她們叫什麼來著
Hey, the girls what were their names?
上面寫…溫克艾沃斯兄弟說你偷了他們的創意
They're sayin'... the Winklevoss twins are sayin' that you stole their idea.
我覺得這有點小煩人
I find that to be mildly annoying.
他們覺得這是竊取知識產權
They find it to be Intelectual Property Theft.
- 你瞧… - 你為什麼沒那給我看？
- Look... - Why don't you show it to me?
收信人寫的是我
It was addressed to me
上面說我們的Facebook是竊取了迪維亞·納蘭德拉和溫克艾沃斯兄弟的創意
They're sayin' that we stole theFacebook from Divya Narendra and the Winklevoss...
- 我知道上面寫了什麼 - 真的嗎
- I know what it says. - Did we?
- 什麼真的 - 現在別和我打岔
- Did we what? - Don't screw around with me now.
看著我
Look at me
這封信表示我們可能會面臨起訴
The letter says we could face legal action.
- 不 它表示我可能會面臨起訴 - 這封信是律師發來的 馬克
- No, it says I could face legal action - This is from lawyer, Mark.
他們一定是有什麼原因才會…
They must feel they have some grounds for...
那律師是他們爸爸的法律顧問
The lawyer is their father's house counsel.
他們有什麼原因嗎
Do they have grounds?
原因就是我們的東西很酷很流行 而哈佛關係網很爛很俗套
The grounds are our thing is cool and popular and HarvardConnection is lame.
瓦爾多 我沒用他們的代碼 我發誓 我一條都沒用
Wardo, I didn't use any of their code, I promise, I didn't use anything.
不是造了個漂亮的椅子就等於欠了所有造過椅子的人的錢
Look, a guy who builds a really nice chair doesn't owe money to everyone who's ever built a chair.
是的 他們告訴我他們有個想法 但是我有了個更好的想法
Ok, they came to me with an idea. I had a better one.
你為什麼沒給我看這封信
Why didn't you show me this letter
我覺得沒什麼大不了的
I didn't think it was a big deal
要是出了什麼事 要是出了隨便什麼事
If there's something wrong, if there's ever anything wrong,
你都能和我說的
You can tell me.
我想幫忙
I'm the guy that wants to help.
這是我們倆的事業
This is our thing.
現在 你還有什麼要告訴我的
Now, is there anything that you need to tell me
沒了
No.
我們該怎麼辦
What are we doing about this?
我去了學生法務中心找了個律師 他跟我說回一封信
I went to a 3-L at Student Legal Services and he told me to write them back.
然後你怎麼說
And what did you say?
我們在一月份見面的時候 我就提及了網站的問題
When we met in January, I express my doubts about the site,
還配了圖表 解釋了多少程序我是沒有參與的
where it stood with graphic, how much programming was left that I had not anticipated...
以及網站運作上硬體的缺失
...the lack of hardware we had to deal with the site use,
還有在發佈網站前缺少推廣
the lack of promotion that we go on to successfully launch the website...
這是你第一次提及這些顧慮 對嗎
This was the first time you raised any of those concern, right?
我之前就提到過
I'd raised concerns before.
- 瞎說 不是對我們提 - 先生們
- Bullshit Not to us - Gentlemen.
我在說的是這封信奡ㄗ鴘 一月份的那次見面
I'm talkin about at the meeting in January to which this letter is referring.
對
Yeah.
我重新遣詞造句一下
Let me re-phrase this.
你給我的客戶寫了16封電郵 在前15封中你沒有提到任何顧慮
You sent my client 16 e-mails. In the first 15, you did't raise any concerns
這算個問題嗎
Is that a question?
而在第16封 你提到了關於網站性能的問題
In the 16th e-mail you raised concerns about the site functionality.
- 你是否欺騙了他們6個禮拜 - 沒有
- Were you leading them on for six weeks? - No.
之前你為什麼沒有提到任何顧慮
Why didn't you raise any of these concern before?
- 下雨了 - 抱歉？
- It's raining. - I'm sorry?
開始下雨了
It's just started raining.
扎克伯格先生 您在聽我說話嗎
Mr. Zuckerberg, do I have your full attention?
沒
No.
你覺得你該麼
Do you think I deserve it?
- 什麼 - 你覺得你該聽我說話麼
- What? - Do you think I deserve your full attention?
在質證之前我發過誓 我也不想作假證
I had to swear an oath before we began this deposition, and I don't want to perjure myself,
所以我有法律上的義務說不
So I have a legal obligation to say no.
好吧 不
Okay - no.
你覺得自己沒必要聽我說話
You don't think I deserve your attention.
我覺得如果你的客戶們 想坐在我的肩膀上自稱為巨人
I think if your clients want to sit on my shoulders and call themselves tall,
他們未嘗不可一試
They have the right to give it a try,
但並不意味著我應該坐在這媗尼A們扯謊
But there's no requirement that I enjoy sitting here listening to people lie.
我可以聽一部分 最小的一部分
You have part of my attention. you have the minimum amount.
而我其他的注意力全都回到了 Facebook的辦公室
The rest of my attention is back at the offices of theFacebook,
在那 我的同事和我所做的事情
Where my colleagues and I are doing things that no one in this room,
是這堜狾酗H 特別是你的客戶們在智力上無法勝任的工作
Including and especially your clients, are intellectually or creatively capable of doing.
我是否充分地回答了你紆尊降貴的問題
Did I adequately answer your condescending question?
現在12點45分了 是不是該吃飯去了
I have 12:45, why don't we say that's lunch.
兩點半回來
Back at 02:30.
她們叫什麼
So what were their names?
她們叫克奡絡扣M愛麗絲
Their names are Christy and Alice.
她們今晚就想喝一杯
And They wanna have drinks tonight
我才不管呢
I don't care.
嘿 兄弟 抱歉 呃 有兩個姑娘在堶掛蓁邥O
Hey man, sorry, uhmm, couple of girls refreshing up in there.
真貼心
Sweet...
我們真是好搭檔
We have groupies.
- 我馬上回來 - 嘿 你要去哪兒
- I'll be right back - Hey, where you goin'?
馬克…
Mark...
艾瑞卡
Erica
嘿
Hey
我看到你從那邊來的
I saw you from over there
- 我都不知道你經常來這家俱樂部 - 是第一次
- I don't know you came to this club a lot. - First time.
我也是
Mine too.
我們能單獨談談麼
Can I talk you alone for a second?
我覺得我就留在這兒好了
I think I'm good right here
只是…我想和你單獨談談
I just... I'd love to talk you alone
- 我們能找個地方麼 - 這兒就好了
- *** - Right here is fine
我不知道你有沒有聽說 我新上線的一個網站
I don't know if you heard about this new website I launched.
沒聽說
No.
- 那Facebook呢？ - 你在網上罵我是個婊子 馬克
- TheFacebook? - You called me a bitch on internet, Mark.
所以我想和你談談
That's why, I wanna talk to you...
- 在網上啊 - 如果你能夠 所以我來…
- On the internet... - If you could just...That's why I came over
把女人比作家畜嗎
Comparing women to farm animals?
我最終並沒有這麼做
I didn't end up doing that.
但你還是寫了這樣的句子
It didn't stop you from writing it.
好像你腦的想法都這麼聰明 不分享倒成了罪過了
As if every thought that tumbles through your head is so clever, it would be a crime for it not to be share.
網上的東西可不是能擦掉的 馬克 寫了就永遠擺在那兒了
The internet's not written in pencil, Mark, it's written in ink,
而你說艾瑞卡·奧布萊特是個婊子
And you published that Erica Albright was a bitch.
然後又誇誇其談侮辱了我的姓氏 還有我的胸圍尺寸
Right before you made some ignorant crack about my family's name, my bra size...
然後根據女人的熱辣程度 來給她們排名次
And then rated women based on their hotness.
- 艾瑞卡 出了什麼事麼 - 不 沒事
- Erica, is there a problem? - No, there's no problem.
你坐在陰暗的小房間媬堥諤 因為這年頭就流行這麼發洩怒火
You write your snide bullshit from a dark room because that's what the angry do nowadays.
我對你挺好的 別這樣折騰我
I was nice to you don't torture me for it.
如果我們找個地方好好談談…
If we could just go somewhere for a minute...
我不想得罪我的朋友
I don't want to be rude to my friends,
- 好吧 - 好吧
- Okay. - Okay.
祝你的遊戲好運
Good luck with your video game.
兄弟 這樣很好
Dude, that's was great...
道歉是件好事 不是麼
That was right thing to do, you apologize, right?
- 我們得擴展 - 什麼 馬克？
- We have to expand. - ***
他生氣了嗎
Is he mad about something?
好的 擴展到耶魯和哥倫比亞大學
Okay, we're expanding to Yale and Columbia.
達斯丁 我想讓你和我一起編寫代碼
Dustin, I want you to share the coding work with me.
克奡 你負責公關事務和業務拓展
Chris, you're gonna be in charge of publicity and outreach.
你可以去BU學生報上登一篇文章 作為溝通的橋樑
You can start by gettin' a story in B.U student newspaper. It's the bridge.
他們討厭有關哈佛的報道
They hate doing stories about Harvard.
報紙編輯堛眯w有人是計算機專業的
Somebody at the newspaper will be a computer science major.
告訴他們馬克·扎克伯格願意 給他們寫十個小時的程序
Tell 'em Mark Zuckerberg will do 10 hours of free programming for them.
- 你為什麼要在BU報上登？ - 因為我想
- Why do you want a story in the B.U. newspaper... - Because I do.
好了 協議就這樣了 愛德華多是首席財務官 擁有公司百分之三十的股份
Now, here's the arrangement. Eduardo's CFO and owns 30% of the company.
達斯丁是副總裁及編程組的負責人 從我這兒拿百分之五的股份
Dustin's Vice President and Head of Programming and his 5% of the company will come from my end.
克奡筋O公關主任 他的報酬視其業務效果而定
Chris is Director of Publicity and his compensation will depend on the amount of work he ends up doing.
- 還有問題嗎 - 這些姑娘是誰
- Any questions? - Who the girls?
抱歉 呃 她們是克奡絡扣M愛麗絲
Sorry, uhmm... they are Christy and Alice.
- 嗨 - 嗨  你好
- Hi... - Hi. Hello.
我們能幫上忙嗎
Is there anything we can do?
不 就這樣了
No, that's it.
耶魯和哥倫比亞 開始吧
Yale and Columbia, let's go.
- 還有斯坦福 - 什麼
- And Stanford... - What?
斯坦福 該讓身處帕羅奧多的人 也見識下這個了
Standford. It's time for them to see this in Palo Alto.
- 你不吃午飯 - 不了
- You don't want any lunch? - No.
我的沙拉可以分你一點
You're welcome to some salad.
不 謝了
No, thank you.
這對你肯定很艱難
This must be hard.
你是誰
Who are you?
- 我叫瑪麗琳·德爾皮 早上自我介紹過 - 我是說 你是幹什麼的
- I'm Marylin Delpy, I introduced myself this morning. - I mean, what do you do?
我在事務所堣u作了兩年
I'm a second year associate at the firm.
老闆讓我在質證的時候坐在桌子邊
My boss wanted me to sit in on the deposition phase.
你在做什麼
What are you doin'?
看看波斯尼亞的情況如何
Checking in to see how it's going in Bosnia.
波斯尼亞？
Bosnia?
他們沒有公路卻有Facebook？
They don't have roads but they have Facebook.
你一定很討厭溫克艾沃斯家的雙胞胎
You must really hate the Winklevoss.
我誰也不討厭
I don't hate anybody.
溫克艾沃斯倆不是因我竊取知識產權而告我
The Winklevii aren't suing me for intellectual property theft.
他們告我是因為他們人生中第一次
They're suing me because for the first time in their lives,
事情沒有按照他們想的那樣發展
Things didn't work at the way they were supposed to for them.
- 他要拓展業務 - 什麼
- He's expanding. - What?
他要把網站拓展到耶魯 哥大和斯坦福 明天這就會出現在校報上
He's expanding to Yale, Columbia and Stanford, it's gonna be in the Crimson tomorrow.
- 真的嗎 - 對
- Really? - Yeah.
看來禁止真把他嚇住了哈
Well, it's look like that Cease and desist letter really scared the shit out of him, huh?
我想請個律師起草一份指令性文件 強迫他關閉網站
I want to hire a lawyer to file for injunctive relief and get this website taken down now!
這網站存在得越久 "哈佛關係網"就越不值錢
Every minute, the site's up, Harvard Connection become less valuable.
我要讓他關網站 我要破壞 我要嚴厲的懲罰 我要讓他去死
I want an injunction, I want damages, punitive relief and I want him dead.
我也一樣
I want those things too!
那為什麼我們什麼都不做 就因為我們是"哈佛紳士"？
Then why aren't we doing anything about it?! Because we're gentlemen of Harvard?!
因為你沒有想過那看起來像什麼
Because you're not thinking about how it's gonna look.
像什麼
How's it gonna look?
就像我們穿著骨骼裝追著 小屁孩在高中體育館娷集曊]
Like my brother and I are in skeleton costumes chasing the Karate Kid around a high school gym.
Cam 他已經觸犯了馬薩諸塞州法律
Cam, he violated Massachusetts state law.
如果他拓展到康涅狄格 紐約 加州 那他就會觸犯聯邦法律
When he goes to Connecticut, New York and California he'll have violated federal law.
同時他還觸犯了哈佛法律
And by the way, he's in violation of Harvard law.
哪來的什麼哈佛法律
There's no such thing as Harvard law.
等等 有的
Wait, Yes, there is.
哈佛學生手冊
Harvard student handbook.
新生人手一本 書埵陪茼a方說…
Every freshman is issued one of this. Somewhere in this book says...
不能偷竊其他學生的東西
You can't steal from another student.
正是我們需要的
This is what we needed.
我要去找薩默斯
****
你沒法見到拉堙P薩默斯
You can't get a meeting with Larry Summers.
我們兩兄弟交昂貴的學費 績點3.9
My brother and I pay tuition at this school, we carry a 3.9 GPA at this school,
我們給學校贏獎盃 還代表學校參加奧運划艇比賽
We've won trophies for this school and We'll be rowing in the Olympics for this school.
而我現在要去見這學校的校長
I want a meeting with the goddamn president of this school.
為什麼要選斯坦福
Why Stanford?
你以為呢
W- Why do you think?
不好意思 我的生化課要遲到了
I'm sorry, I'm late for Bio Chem..
好吧
Okay.
你還不知道我的名字吧
You don't know my name, do you?
斯坦福嗎
Is it Stanford?
我真應該海扁你一頓
I should just kick your ass.
你怎麼能去了派對 認識女生然後…
How you go to party and you meet somebody...
艾米莉亞·堹S 不過你更喜歡人家叫你艾米 來自奧林達
Amelia Ritter, but you prefer Amy. You're from Orinda
你父親是房地產經紀 你母親是個酒鬼
Your father in commercial real estate and your mother is 10 years sober.
我讀什麼專業
What's my major?
- 長號 - 是嗎
- Trombone. - Really?
我記得是有關長號的
I remember something about a trombone.
你和美女上床 卻轉頭就忘
"Tu fais l'amour ?la jolie fille et la mets de ce? (You make love to the pretty girl and put it aside)
- 法語 - 正是
- French... - Oui
- 你是學法語專業的 - 你呢
- Your major is French. - And yours?
我？
Mine?
我沒有專業
I don't have one.
你沒有申請專業嗎
You haven't declared?
我不上學
I don't go to school.
- 開玩笑呢吧 - 沒有
- You kidding? - No.
那你在哪上過學
Where did you go to school?
上過幾年威廉小學
William Elementary for a little while,
說真的 你又不是15歲
Seriously, you're not like 15 years old or anything are you?
不是
No.
- 你不是15歲吧？ - 不是
- But you're not like 15, are you? - No.
你到底是做什麼的
So what do you do?
我是個企業家
I'm an entrepreneur.
- 你沒工作吧 - 我不會那樣說
- You're unemployed. - I wouldn't say that.
那你會怎麼說
What would you say?
我說我是個企業家
That I'm an entrepreneur.
好吧 那你的企業是什麼
Well then, what was your latest preneur?
我創辦了一家互聯網公司 可以讓人們免費下載音樂
Well, I founded an internet company that let folks download and share music for free.
- 像Napster那樣？ - 跟Napster一模一樣
- Kinda like Napster? - Exactly like Napster.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
我創辦了Napster
I founded Napster.
- 肖恩·帕克創辦了Napster - 很高興見到你
- Sean Parker founded Napster. - Nice to meet you.
你是肖恩·帕克？
You're Sean Parker.
啊哈 你看見桌子旁邊…那只鞋了吧
Ah, you see, the shoe's on the other, uh, table which has turned.
- 我和肖恩·帕克一起睡了？ - 你還上了肖恩·帕克
- I just slept with Sean Parker? - You just slept on Sean Parker.
你是億萬富翁
You're zillionaire.
- 不完全是 - 那你是什麼
- Not technically - What are you?
窮光蛋 免費音樂本來就沒什麼錢賺
Broke. There's not a lot of money in free music.
還得被所有得了格萊美獎的人告
Even less when you're being sued by everyone who's ever been to the Grammys.
- 我有些犯暈了 - 我很榮幸
- This is blowing my mind. - I appreciate that
我得去沖個澡 然後去上課了
I gotta hop in the shower and get ready for class.
生化課 我還知道你學法語 名字叫艾米
Biochem, even know you are in French major, whose name is Amy.
你及格了
You passed.
我很勤奮好學的
I'm a hard worker.
那有果汁 還有些別的 請自便
There's juice or anything else you can find. Help yourself.
- 你不介意我看看我的郵件吧 - 只管用吧
- You mind if I check my e-mail? - Yeah. go ahead.
艾米
Amy...
艾米？
Amy?
- 哎 - 你能出來一下嗎
- Yeah! - Can you come out here?
稍等
Just a second!
- 這埵陶D 艾米 - 什麼
- There's a snake in here, Amy. - What?
哪兒
Where?
這堥S蛇 不過我要問你點事
Ok, there isn't snake but I need to ask you something.
- 你是在搞笑嗎 會出人命的 - 怎麼出人命
- Are you kidding me? I could've been killed! - How?
跑太快 被纏住…
By running to you fast and gettin' twisted...
你要問什麼
What do you need to ask me?
我想看郵件 然後看到你電腦媔}了個網站
I went to check my e-mail and there's a website open on your computer.
是的 昨晚你睡過去之後 我就想小上了一下Facebook
Yeah. After you passed out last night, I went on theFacebook for 'lil bit.
那是什麼
What's that?
The Facebook？ 已經在斯坦福風靡兩周了
TheFacebook? Standford had it for, like two weeks now.
超級酷 就是有點讓人上癮
It's really awesome except it's freakishly addictive.
說真的 我至少一天要上五次
Seriously, I'm on the thing like five times a day.
你不介意我發個郵件吧
You mind if I set myself an e-mail.
- 行啊 沒事吧 - 沒事
- Yes, everything okay? - Everything's great.
我只是要找一下…
I just need to find...
你 馬克·扎克伯格
You, Mark Zuckerberg.
我從來沒來過這棟建築
I've never been in this building before.
這建築比美國還歷史悠久
This building is a hundred years older than the country it's in.
所以千萬小心點
So do be careful.
我們好好地坐在椅子上呢
We're sitting in the chairs.
喂 很好
Yes. Very good.
你們可以進去了
You can go in now.
那是他們自己太蠢了 我本該在那的
That's just their own stupidity, I should have been there.
黑暗是因為缺少了光 而他們愚蠢就是因為缺少了我
Darkness is the absence of light and stupidity in that instance was the absence of me.
凱瑟琳 有兩個學生來找我 本科生
Catherine, I've got students in my office now. Students. Undergrads.
從樣子來看 像是要給我推銷 布魯克斯兄弟牌西裝的
I don't know, from the looks of it, they want to sell me Brooks Brothers Franchise. Alright.
- 早上好 - 早上好 校長
- Good morning. - Good morning, Sir.
我是卡梅隆·溫克艾沃斯 這是我弟弟泰勒
I'm Cameron Winklevoss and this is my brother, Tyler.
你們來這是因為…
And you here, because...
你們任一個回答都行
Either of you can answer.
我以為你在看信
I thought you were reading the letter.
我已經看完了
I've read the letter.
我們想到了一個網站的創意 叫做"哈佛關係網"
Well, we came up with an idea for a website called HarvardConnection...
現在改名叫"聯結你我"
That we've since changed the name to ConnectU,
- 但馬克·扎克伯格剽竊了我們的創意 - 我懂了
- And Mark Zuckerberg stole that idea... - I'm understand.
我想知道你們要我幹什麼
I'm asking what you want me to do about it?
先生 在分發給新生的學生手冊
Well Sir, in The Harvard Student Handbook, which is distributed to each freshman...
在"哈佛行為準則"一欄下面
Under the heading "Standards of Conduct in the Harvard Community"
寫道 學校希望所有的學生
It says, The College expects that all students to be honest...
誠實守信以及行為正直
And forthcoming in their dealings with members in this community.
要求學生尊重公眾和私人物品
Students are required to respect public and private ownership.
偷竊行為 侵吞財產或是…
Instances of theft, misappropriation or...
- 安 - 在
- Ann... - Yes Sir.
打醒我吧 繼續
Punch me in the face... Go ahead.
或是未授權的盜用都要受處分
Or unauthorized use will result in disciplinary action,
甚至可能被退學
Including the requirement to withdraw from the College.
記憶力不錯 然後呢
You memorize that instead of doing, what?
我們兩兄弟今天來 是想問問您…
What my brother and I come, here today, to ask you, respectfully of course...
竊取其他學生的成果是違反校規的 就這麼簡單
Sir, it's against University rules to steal from another student, plain and simple.
你和你們的宿管談過了？
You've spoken to your House-master.
是的 先生 宿管讓我們找行政委員會 但行政委員會不睬我們
Yes Sir, and the House-master made a recommendation to the Ad Board but the Ad Board won't hear us.
你們有沒有直接和那個學生談過
Have you tried dealing with the other student directly?
扎克伯格先生過去兩周都沒有回復過我們的任何郵件或電話
Mr. Zuckerberg hasn't been responding to any of our e-mails or phone calls for the last two weeks.
我們去敲他宿舍的門他都不應
He doesn't answer when we knock on his door at Kirkland.
我最近一次當面見到他還是在庭院
And the closest I've come to dealing with him face to face is when I saw him on the quad,
然後我追著他跑了整個哈佛操場
And I chased him through Harvard Square.
你追逐他？
You chased him?
我看見他了 而且我知道他也看見我了 然後過了幾分鐘他就消失了
I- I saw him and I know he saw me and after a minutes he disappeared.
我不覺得這是學校的事
I don't see this as the university issue.
這顯然是學校的事
Of course this is a university issue.
學校有關於道德和榮譽的準則 而他將兩者都打破了
There's a code of ethics and an honor code and he violated them both.
你們和學校之間有道德契約 但彼此間沒有
You entered into a code of ethics with the university, not with each other.
很抱歉Summers校長 你說的完全沒道理
I'm sorry President Summers, but what you just said makes no sense to me at all.
我很震驚
I'm devastated by that.
我弟弟是想說 如果馬克·扎克伯格闖進了我們宿舍
What my brother means is if Mark Zuckerberg breaking into our dorm room
偷走了我們的電腦 那就是學校的事了
And stole our computer, that would be university issue.
我不知道校長辦公室還要管小偷竊
I don't know this office doesn't handle petty larceny.
這不是小偷竊 這是價值百萬美金的創意
This isn't petty larceny. This idea potentially worth millions of dollars.
- 百萬美金 - 對
- Millions? - Yes.
你們想像力太豐富了
You might just be letting your imaginations run away with you.
先生 我不覺得你有資格這樣說
Sir, I actually don't think you're in any position to make that call.
我是美國財政秘書 我有資格這樣說
I was the U.S. Treasury Secretary, I'm in some position to make that call
讓我們充分發揮想像力正是你在新生入學典禮演講時說的啊
Letting our imaginations run away with us is exactly what we were told us to do in your freshmen address.
我建議你們在想新項目時發揮想像力
I would suggest that you let your imaginations run away with you on a new project.
- 是嗎 - 當然 哈佛堥C個人都在發明新東西
- You would? - Yes, everyone at Harvard is eventing something.
哈佛的本科生相信創造工作比找工作更好
Harvard Undergraduates believe that inventing a job is better than finding a job.
所以我再次建議你們倆想個新項目
So I suggest again that the two of you come up with a new, new project.
不好意思 但那不是重點 先生
I'm sorry, but that's not the point, Sir.
那重點是什麼
Please what's the point.
要辨別是非不需要是這方面的專家
You don't have to be an intellectual property expert to understand the difference between right and wrong.
你是說我不能辨別是非
And you're saying that I don't.
我絕無此意
Of course I'm not saying that.
我正有此意
I'm saying that.
- 是嗎 - 先生
- Really? - Sir...
安 他們怎麼得到預約的
Ann... How do they get this appointment?
他們父親的同事
Colleagues of their father...
我來說清楚 兩位溫克艾沃斯先生 既然你們要討論是非
Let me tell you something Mr. Winklevoss, Mr. Winklevoss, since you under subject of right and wrong.
你們這種行為 到這堥茖ㄖ痟N是錯的
This action, this meeting, the two of you being here is wrong.
這不是哈佛學生該做的事 也不是哈佛的精神
Is not worthy of Harvard, Is not what Harvard saw in you...
沒有特殊對待
You don't get special treatment!
我們沒有要求特殊對待
We never ask for it...
只是想新項目嗎 就像科研課上做模型一樣？
Just start another project? Like we're making a diorama for the science fair?
- 如果你有什麼問題 溫克艾沃斯先生 - 我們從沒要求特殊對待
- If you have problems with that Mr. Winklevoss - We never ask for special treatment.
法庭隨時向你們敞開
The court are always at your disposal...
還有什麼我能幫到你們的嗎
Is there anything else, I could do for you?
- !@#$%^&… - 閉嘴
- *** - *****
感謝您抽出寶貴的時間 先生
Thank you very much for your time, Sir.
哎呀 弄壞了你們335年歷史的門把手
Ups, broke 335 years old your door knob.
愛德華多 春假期間 你和扎克伯格先生去了趟紐約
Eduardo, spring break, you and Mr. Zuckerberg took a trip to New York.
- 對 - 此行的目的是什麼
- yes. - What was the purpose of the trip?
作為財務總監 我要去和潛在廣告商洽談
Well, as CFO, I'd set up some meetings with potential advertisers.
你們去是誰出的錢
Who paid for the trip?
來自我幾個月前存的一千美金
It was paid for out of the thousand dollar account I'd set up a few months earlier.
在那時你的一千美金是公司唯一資金
At this point your thousand dollars was the only money that had been put into the company.
- 對 - 洽談進行得如何
- Yes. - How did you feel the meetings went?
- 很糟糕 - 為什麼
- It went terribly. - Why?
- 馬克睡著了 - 我沒睡著
- Mark was asleep. - I was not asleep.
我能重新說一遍嗎
Can I re-phrase my answer?
我倒是希望他睡了
I wish he'd been asleep.
我們現在覆蓋29個學校 有75000多個會員
So we're at 29 schools now with over 75.000 members.
人們上the Facebook的時間比其他網站都長
People who go on theFacebook tend to stay on longer than almost any other website.
最驚人的數據是 61%初始用戶都會成為回頭客
Now here's the most impressive statistic, 61% of people who try it once, will come back...
- 如果你能讓我… - 抱歉 等一下
- Now if you'll allow me... - Excuse me, one second...
他發出的是什麼聲音 是"切"嗎
What sound that he's making? Is that like a tsk...
不是"切" 是…
It wasn't tsk...
像火雞叫
Like a glottal stop.
喉嚨塞住了似的
Almost a gag reflex.
你們這是什麼意思
Guys, what is this?
紐約之行還有一次會面
There was one more meeting scheduled for the New York trip.
對 是頓晚餐
Yes, it was a dinner.
那時是我女朋友安排的
It was set up through my girlfriend at the time.
你覺得馬克對這次會面很期待嗎
Would you say that Mark was excited about this meeting?
是的 十分期待
Yes, very.
- 他們不會把我們丟出去的 - 說不定呢
- Look, they're not gonna card us... - They might.
- 看看四周 - 這很尷尬
- I mean look around. - It'll be embarrassing.
告訴他我們不會被丟出去
Tell him they're not gonna card us.
- 他們不會丟我們出去 - 馬克
- They're not gonna card us. - Mark...
你又想說廣告的事嗎
Are you gonna talk about ads again?
除非是想做哈特福德芭蕾劇場 不然做生意就是要盈利的
Unless you're the Ballet Theatre of Hartford, the purpose of a business is to make a profit.
這還不是生意
This isn't a business, yet.
那我怎麼辦 我的工作就是…算了
That's tough for me because my job... Nevermind.
他晚了25分鐘
He's 25 mins late.
他19歲就創辦了Napster 他可以放人鴿子
He founded Napster when he was 19, he can be late.
- 他又不是神 - 那他是什麼
- He's not a God. - Then what is he?
他是遲到25分鐘的人
He's 25 minutes late.
我覺得瓦爾多嫉妒了
I think Wardo's jealous.
我絕對不是在嫉妒 我是緊張
I honestly wasn't jealous. I was nervous.
為什麼
Why?
我完全不認識他 但我據我的瞭解
I didn't know him at all but I had done a search and asked around...
他給我的印象是個很麻煩的人
He struck me as kind of a wild card.
為什麼
Why?
他整垮了兩家很牛的互聯網公司
He crashed out of two pretty big internet companies in spectacular fashion,
- 他還是個癮君子 - 但那些公司也是他創辦的
- He's had a reputation with drugs. - He also founded the companies.
我們不需要他
We don't need him.
他來了
He's here.
不不 沒事 吃你們的
No, no, take your time.
他戴表了
And he does own a watch.
別說了
Stop it.
- 我是肖恩·帕克 - 你好
- I'm Sean Parker. - How do you do.
你們一定是愛德華多 克奡絡扣M馬克 見到你們真高興
You must be Eduardo and Christy and Mark, great to meet you.
見到你很高興
Great to meet you.
你們還沒點東西吃呢
You guys don't have anything in front of you.
- 托 - 我們一直在等…
- Tori... - We were waiting...
- 行了 - 你能不能給我們來點
- Hey baby boy. - Could you bring out some things?
帶薑汁的豬肉 金槍魚 還有龍蝦之類的開胃菜
The lacquered pork with that ginger confit, tuna tartar, and the lobster claws, that'll get us started.
克奡絡 想喝點什麼
Christy what do you like to drink?
蘋果馬蒂尼
An appletini
不錯 來四杯吧
Great. Four of those.
那之後就是他的個人秀了
From that point on it was a Sean-a-thon.
問題在於你們談了什麼
The question was what did you talk about?
他滔滔不絕地說Napster
He took us through his episode with Napster.
我不想把我的二十歲年華浪費在辯護上
I didn't want to spend my twenty as a professional defendant
誰知道音樂行業沒點幽默感
Who knew the music industry doesn't have a sense of humor.
我們打算賣掉公司來償還 欠他們所謂的三千五百萬版稅
We tried to sell the company to pay the 35 millions they said we owed in royalties,
不過我想對他們來說 這有點像用偷來的卡付偷來的汽油的錢
But I guess to them that was a little like selling a stolen card to pay for the stolen gas.
所以我們就說 去你媽的 然後就宣佈了破產
So we said, screw it, we declare bankruptcy.
- 你一舉成名了 - 而你的飲料喝完了
- You made a name for yourself. - And you are dry.
- 托 - 不 不用了
- Tory... - No, no, I'm good.
然後他又開始講他第二次冒險 網絡通訊錄
And then he went to his second business venture which was an online rolodex.
他被"追逐平等"網站給踢出來了
which was an online Rolodex that he got thrown out of by Case Equity.
這次我想 要好好幹 我繫了領帶 把皮鞋擦得珵亮
And I want to do it nice this time, I put on a tie, i shine my shoes.
但沒人願意接小孩子的訂單
But nobody want to take orders from a kid.
讓我告訴你們接下來發生了什麼
So let me tell you what happen...
- 我不是精神科醫生 但是… - 我知道你不是
- I'm not psychiatrist, but - I'm glad with got that on record.
你不是精神科醫生 然後呢
You're not a psychiatrist, but what...
精神科醫生會說他得了妄想癥
A psychiatrist would say that he was paranoid.
他們請了私人偵探 日夜跟蹤我
They hire private detectives, who follow you day and night.
你是專業偵探的目標
You are target for hi press-escort.
我沒有證據 但我知道他們竊聽了我的電話
I can't prove it but I know they tap my phone.
只要能找到任何整垮我的證據
Whatever it is that's gonna trip you up, you're done already.
隨著時間推移 做事要越來越小心
Private behaviour is really cover time gone by...
然後不知怎麼的 你就過上了達賴喇嘛一樣的生活
And then somehow and someway you've manage to live your life like a Dalai lama
別搞錯了
Don't mixed it up.
他們想要的不是你 是你的創意
Because they don't want you, they want your idea.
而且他們想讓你說謝謝
And they want you to say thank you while you,
就是…在被他們扇了一耳光之後
Excuse me... wipe your chin and walk away.
這是發生在你身上的事？
That's what happen to you?
絕對的妄想
And delusional.
對
Yes,
但 他們總有一天要還的
But... they'll be pay back.
我曾經用Napster打垮唱片公司 這次也是一樣
In case I brought down the record company with Napster and I left the company since then too.
抱歉 你沒有整垮唱片公司 是他們贏了
Sorry, you didn't bring down the record companies. They won.
- 在法庭上 - 對
- In court. - Yeah.
你現在還想買唱片嗎 愛德華多
You wanna buy a Tower record, Eduardo?
然後他不停地說他在硅谷的生活
And he told story after story about life in Silicon Valley,
斯坦福的派對 還有在洛杉磯的百萬富翁朋友
Parties at Stanford and down in LA, friends who'd become millionaires,
不過主要是為什麼馬克一定要… 一定要去加州
But mostly how Mark had to, he had to come to California.
然後他終於說到the Facebook
And then he cut around to theFacebook.
跟我說說你們的進展吧
So tell me about your progress.
我們覆蓋了29所大學 已經有75000多個會員
Well, we're in 29 schools now, we got over 75 thousands members...
說說你們的戰略
Tell me about the strategy.
好吧 比如 我們想入駐德州的貝勒大學 但貝勒大學已經有了一個校園社交網絡
Ok, for instance, we wanted Baylor in Texas but Baylor already had a social network on campus
所以我們並不直接去找他們 而是列出了他們周圍所有學校
So instead of going right after them, we made a list of every school within a hundred miles
然後先讓the Facebook入駐這些校園
And put theFacebook on those campuses first.
不久之後所有貝勒大學的學生就會在我們的網站上找到他們的朋友
Pretty soon all the Baylor kids were seeing their friends on our site.
- 我們就成功入駐了 - 小餌釣大魚
- We were in. - Its called a little bait for a big one.
- 很聰明啊 馬克 - 謝謝 那是我的主意
- That's smart, Mark. - Thanks that's was mine.
放鬆點
Easy.
不如你來說說看
Hey you know what, settle an argument for us,
我覺得the Facebook是時候開始盈利了
I say it's time to start making money from theFacebook
但馬克不想要廣告 你覺得誰對
But Mark doesn't want advertising. Who's right?
你們都不對
Neither of you yet.
the Facebook很酷
TheFacebook is cool,
- 這應該長久保持 - 對
- That's what it's got going for it. - Yeah.
你想用廣告毀了它
You don't want to ruin it with ads
- 因為廣告不酷 - 正是
- Because ads aren't cool. - Exactly.
這就像你們在校園媟d一場盛大的派對
It's like you're throwing the greatest party on campus.
但有人說 十一點必須結束
And someone's saying, it's gotta be over by 11:00.
正是如此
That's exactly right.
你們還不知道這到底是什麼呢
You don't even know what the thing is yet.
能做多大 能走多遠
How big it can get and how far it can go.
這還不該是停手的時候
This is no time to take your chips down.
一百萬美元不夠酷 你們知道什麼才叫酷嗎
A million dollars isn't cool. You know what's cool?
你？
You?
十億美元
A billion dollars.
然後大家就都安靜了
And that shut everybody up.
這才是你們的目標 十億美金的價值
And that's where you're headed. A billion dollar valuation.
除非你們聽了壞建議 雖然那樣你們仍能做成功的連鎖酸奶店
Unless you take bad advice in which case you might as well come up with a chain of very successful yogurt shop.
去釣魚時 你可以釣很多小魚 也可以只釣一隻大魚
When you go fishing you can catch a lot of fish or you can catch a big fish.
你會走進一個人房間 看到他和14磅鱒魚的合影嗎
You ever walk into a guy's den and see a picture of him standing next to fourteen trout?
不 他一定是抱著3000磅的槍魚
No he's holding an 3000 pound marlin.
- 對 - 好比喻
- Yup. - That's a good announce.
但我們都知道槍魚不可能有3000磅重不是嗎
But we all know, that marlin won't weight 3000 pounds, right?
- 我見過差不多那麼大的 - 我從沒見過
- I've seen a big one at close - No, I haven't.
但那傢伙要抱著像路虎那麼大的魚
But I don't think the guy holdings a marlin at size of a range rover.
那得是多大的魚 多壯的人啊
That would really big fish or a very strong guy.
你沒搞清楚重點吧
You think I might be getting away from the point?
我不是來惹麻煩的
I don't have a dog in this fight.
我只是個粉絲 過來打聲招呼
I'm just a fan who came to say hi.
他那晚之後就完全抓住了馬克的心
He owned Mark after that dinner.
他告訴馬克很快會再談 拿起賬單 然後就走了
He picked up the check, He told Mark they'd talk again soon and he was gone.
不過臨走他還做了對公司的一次重大貢獻
But not before he made his biggest contribution to the company.
把"the"去掉 只留Facebook
Drop the "the". Just Facebook.
更簡潔
It's cleaner.
靠
Shit.
那都可以破說話速度的世界紀錄了
That's gotta be some kind of land speed record for talking.
你想讓派對在十一點結束嗎
You want to end the party at eleven?
我要為派對付錢
I'm trying to pay for the party.
如果不酷的話就根本不叫派對了
There won't be a party unless it's cool.
你覺得呢
What'd you think?
是啊 好吧 把"the"去掉
Yes, sure, let's drop the "the"
我是說丟掉14磅鱒魚 去抓槍魚 這聽起來不是很棒嗎
I meant catching the marlin instead of the 14 trouts. Doesn't that sound good?
鱒魚才這麼覺得
If you're a trout.
我要把這些加入記錄
I'm going to enter this into the record.
Facebook的合併文件 以及在佛羅里達註冊的有限公司
Incorporation papers for Facebook, and LLC registered in Florida,
- 為什麼在佛羅里達註冊 - 我家在那
- Why Florida? - That's where my family lives.
文件中對合併後股權分配說明如下
And ask the respondent to stipulate that the documents of incorporation state the ownership as follows,
65%歸馬克·扎克伯格所有
Sixty-five percent for Mark Zuckerberg,
30%歸愛德華多·薩佛林 5%歸屬達斯丁·莫斯克維茨
30 percent for Eduardo Saverin and 5 percent for Dustin Moskowitz.
- 是做出了規定 - 是在2004年4月13日簽的
- We stipulate. - And that was April 13th 2004.
你可以標一下
You can mark it.
還有什麼問題嗎
Do you have anything here?
是的 謝謝 薩佛林先生
Yes, thank you. Mr. Saverin,
你做過什麼可以合法終止合同的事嗎
Have you ever done anything that might be considered legitimate ground for termination?
沒有
No.
你從沒做過使公司名譽受損 或者危及公司的事嗎
You never did anything to embarrass the company or even seriously jeopardize it?
沒有
No.
沒有？
No?
- 沒有 - 你曾經被控虐待動物
- No. - You were accused of animal cruelty.
等一下
Wait.
- 你沒有嗎 - 這…這不是事實
- You weren't? - T- this not happening.
我這有篇校報的報道
I have here an article from The Crimson...
上帝啊
Jesus Christ...
我完全不能接受 瓦爾多
I can't have this, Wardo.
拜託 這是狗屎 這只是社團的惡作劇
Come on, man this is bullshit, this is another clubs playing a prank.
我即將加入鳳凰社 而作為加入的考驗
I'd gotten into the Phoenix. I'd been accepted and as part of my initiation,
我必須一整個星期隨身攜帶並照顧一隻雞
I had to, for one week, carry with me all the times and take care of a chicken.
他們將你作為the Facebook創始人之一 "小愛德華多·薩佛林"
They identify you as one of the founders of theFacebook, "Junior Eduardo Saverin,"
我雖然不是專家 但也知道被扯上虐待動物對我們的事業不利
I'm not the expert but being connected to torturing animals is probably bad for business.
我沒有虐待那隻雞 我不虐雞 你們瘋了嗎
I did not torture the chicken, I don't torture chickens, are you crazy?
不 冷靜點
No, and settle down, please.
我這埵魚g校報的報道
I have here, an article from The Crimson...
- 這真尖刻 - 956
- This is scathing. - Nine-hundred-fifty-six.
我當時和馬克在宿舍食堂吃飯
I was having dinner in the Kirkland Dining Hall with Mark,
我帶著那隻雞是因為我必須時刻帶著它 這就是大學生活
And I had the chicken with me because I had to have the chicken with me at all times. This was college.
總得有人出來澄清一下啊
Somebody gonna have to answer for this.
九百六十九
Nine-hundred-sixty-nine.
食堂用雞做菜 而我要餵我的雞
Dining hall was serving chicken for dinner and I had to feed my chicken.
所以我只好餵了點雞肉給雞吃
So I took... Little pieces of chicken and gave it to the chicken.
肯定是有人看見了 因為我接下來就被指控逼迫同類相食了
Someone must have seen me because the next thing I knew I was being accused of forced cannibalism.
我不知道這是不允許的 我和好多動物權益組織聯繫過
I didn't know you could't do that. I dealt with the various animal rights groups,
我也和聯合院長討論過 問題都解決了
I dealt with the Associate Dean of the College, this was all resolved.
九百八十八
Nine-hundred-eighty-eight.
肯定是坡客或福萊的人打了小報告
Someone from the Porc or the Fly must have reported it.
我覺得肯定是溫克艾沃斯
For all I know it was the Winklevoss...
好吧 忘掉它吧
Alright, let's just forget about it.
這太可笑了 我被指控虐待動物 還不如被指控成戀屍癖呢
This is absurd, I'm being accused of animal cruelty. Better to be accused of Necrophilia.
確實還不如被指控戀屍癖啊
It is better to be accused of Necrophilia.
我得向我父親解釋這件事
I have to explain this to my father,
我得向所有人解釋這件事 我要…你在幹什麼
I'm gonna explain this to everybody, I'm gonna... what is happening on that?
我的"戰後時期及當代藝術"馬上要期末考
I have my final coming up for "Postwar and Contemporary Art".
我還沒去上過課呢 我要寫關於這四幅畫的論文
And I haven't been to class. I'm supposed to write about those four paintings.
那是個Facebook的頁面嗎
Is that a facebook page?
對 我用馬甲把畫傳上去 然後讓大家在下面評論
Yeah, I opened it under an alias. I posted the paintings and asked people to comment.
時不時我再上去攪和一下 保持討論氣氛
Every once in a while, I hop on and stir the pot to get a good debate going.
扎克伯格先生在期末考時作弊？
Mr. Zuckerberg was cheating on his final exam?
我不想回答那個 格雷琴
I'd rather not answer that, Gretchen.
為什麼
Then why not?
我不會指控他考試作弊 因為那不是朋友幹的事
Because I'm not suing him for cheating on his final exam and so that's not what friends do.
但你剛剛告訴我們他作弊了
Well you just told us he was cheating.
你告訴你的律師我虐待動物了？
You told your lawyers I was torturing animals?!
不 他什麼也沒告訴我們
No, he didn't tell us about it at all.
我們的訴訟律師有能力找到校報文章
Our litigators are capable of finding Crimson article.
事實上我們跟他說這件事時 他還為你辯護
In fact when we raised the subject with him he defended you.
993 就差一點了
Nine-ninety-three, we are so close.
噢 我想起來了 我們還需要點錢 瓦爾多
Oh yeah, that reminds me, We're gonna need more money, Wardo.
我知道 更多服務器 更多應用…
I agree. More servers, more apps...
我要面試兩個實習生 我們要付他們報酬
I'm interviewing two interns to come to Palo Alto and we're gonna have to pay them something.
抱歉 你說什麼
Sorry what?
我已經在距離斯坦福 兩個街區的地方找到了出租的房子
I already found a house for rent on a street two blocks from the Stanford campus.
非常完美 而且還帶游泳池
It is perfect and it's got a pool.
你什麼時候決定暑假要去加州的
When did you decide to go to California for the summer?
你是問我什麼時候確定的嗎
You mean when did I actually decide?
"肖恩·帕克個人秀"的時候？
Somewhere in the middle of The Sean Parker Variety Hour?
他說得對 我們就該去加州
He was right. California's the place we've gotta be.
你是加德·克拉皮特嗎 (下面所說的節目主角]
Is you Jed Clampett?
你們在巴西也能看到"豪門新人類"？ (美國電影)
You guys got The Beverly Hillbillies in Brazil...
是啊 在巴西也看得到 很好看
Yes, we got the show in Brazil, it was genius.
你到底對肖恩有什麼意見
What is your problem with Sean?
他根本沒有什麼上得了檯面的東西
He doesn't bring anything to the table.
他沒錢 達斯丁編程都比他好
He doesn't have money, Dustin's a better programmer...
他認識風投的人
He's got connections to the VCs.
我們不需要風投 我們需要廣告商 而且我也認識風投的人啊
We don't need VCs, we need advertisers and I've got connections to the VCs.
- 他有經驗而且… - 聽著
- The real players and... - Look
作為一個剛讓公司顏面受損的人
As someone who's really embarrassed the company in a bad way...
那是溫克艾沃斯倆幹的好事 馬克
It was the Winklevosses, Mark!
等一下 點刷新
Hang on. Hit refresh.
十五萬零四
150.004
150000個會員 瓦爾多
150.000 members, Wardo.
- 恭喜你 兄弟 - 恭喜
- Congratulations, dude. - Congratulations.
你不覺得很奇怪嗎 還被私人偵探跟蹤
You don't think it was strange? That he was followed by private detectives?
誰人無錯
Who came up with nothing.
但已經錯到讓他離開公司了 毒品 泡妞…
Enough to get him out of the company. The drugs, the girls...
我們又不知道那些是不是真的
We don't know any of that's true.
你可以去查查看
You can read about it.
我查得到你虐待動物
I can read about your torturing birds. Since when reading something about...
魚就不吃魚了嗎？! 槍魚和鱒魚？
Don't fish eat other fish?! The marlins and the trout?!
他在說什麼
What's he talkin' about?
我明晚十點要去實驗室面試實習生
I'm interviewing interns at 10 tomorrow night in the CS lab.
隨便你怎麼樣 我無語了
Get on board with this man, you know... I don't really know what else to say.
這是在幹什麼
What's goin' on?
他們有十分鐘入侵Python服務器
They have 10 mins to get root access to a Python web server,
破解SSL加密 在安全端口攔截所有流量
Expose its SSL encryption and then intercept all traffic over its secure port.
他們是在黑別人
They're hacking.
都是在Pix防火牆模擬器上 但這正是有趣之處
All behind a Pix Firewall Emulator. But here's the beauty.
你知道我完全聽不懂你在說什麼吧
You know I didn't understand anything you just said, right?
- 我知道 - 所以好玩之處在哪
- I do know that. - So what's the beauty?
每寫十行代碼 就要喝一杯
Every 10th line of code written, they have to take a shot.
而且黑客應該隱蔽
And hacking's supposed to be stealth,
所以服務器每檢測到一次入侵 負責的那個人也要喝一杯
So anytime the server detects an intrusion, the candidate responsible has to take a shot.
我還有個時不時就同時 在五台電腦上跳出窗口的程序
I also have a program running that has a pop-up window appear simultaneously on all five computers...
最後一個點窗口的人也得喝一杯
The last candidate to hit the window has to take a shot.
另外每三分鐘他們也都得喝一杯
Plus every three minutes they all have to take a shot.
三分鐘到
Three minutes.
我能問問實習生工作堶 有什麼部分是需要喝醉的嗎
Can I ask, what part of the interns jobs will they need to be able to do drunk?
對 更應該做的測試是 他們能不能養一個禮拜的雞
You're right. A more relevant test would be seeing if they can keep a chicken alive for a week.
我很刻薄
That was mean.
看
Here...
這是什麼
What is this.
我開了個新賬戶 存進去18000美金
I opened a new account and put $18.000 in it.
那夠暑假用嗎
Will that get you through the summer?
歡迎加入Facebook
Welcome to Facebook.
- 18000美元 - 對
- $18.000 - Yes.
- 外加你已經投入的1000美元 - 對
- In addition to the $1000 you'd already put up. - Yes.
總共是19000美元
A total of $19.000 now.
- 對 - 等等
- Yes. - Hang on.
我只是檢查一下計算
I'm just checking your math on that.
對 我也得到了同樣的結果
Yes, I got the same thing.
我能繼續了嗎
May I continue?
在表達了對扎克伯格先生暑假把公司搬到加州去的憂慮後
After expressing misgivings about Mr. Zuckerberg taking the company and moving it to California for the summer,
你為什麼改變心意給他18000美元
Why did you turn around and put $18.000 in an account for his use?
我覺得我們是夥伴 我們是團隊
I figured we were partners. I wanted to be a team player.
我覺得馬克 達斯丁還有新的實習生
I figured Mark, Dustin and the new interns could work on the site.
在我去紐約尋求商機的期間 可以做好網站的工作
While I was on generating advertiser interest in New York.
不過我更多是覺得 就三個月能出什麼事
But mostly I figured, how much could possibly go wrong in three months?
上上上
go.go...
我沒死
I didn't die.
我知道
I know.
- 我做到了 - 確實
- I made it. - You did.
我跳了八米遠
That was like an 8.
最多兩米
That was like a 2.
- 不是吧 - 沒錯
- It was better than that. - Yeah.
- 我沒事 - 你確定？
- I'm ok. - You sure...
對
yeah.
呀
Yikes.
門鈴響了
That's the doorbell
我不知道我們還有門鈴
I don't know we had a door bell.
- 安德魯 去開門 - 他才不會去開呢
- Andrew get the door. - No, he's wired in.
我們的安全押金要沒了
That's gonna cut into the security deposit.
- 安德魯 不錯 - 現在不行
- Andrew... Not now. - Good boy
- 肖恩 - 馬克
- Sean - Mark.
- 你住這兒？ - 是啊 你也是？
- Do you live here? - Yeah. Do you?
我們就住對門 我們看見煙囪
We were right across the street, we saw the chimney...
- 是的 - 有人受傷嗎
- Yeah - Is anybody hurt?
沒有 你住街對面？
No. You live across the street.
我叫莎倫
I'm Sharon.
這是我的…莎倫 她也住街對面 我正要幫她搬家 然後就看到煙囪
This is my... Sharon. She lives across the street and I was helping her move out when we saw the chimney...
對 我們做了個滑索通往泳池
Yeah, we had a zip line to the pool.
你終於來加州了
You came to California.
對
Yeah.
你做了正確的選擇
You made the right choice.
接著
Here you go.
莎倫
Sharon.
- 對不起 - 沒事
- I'm so sorry. - No problem
- 我不知道你要… - 再給你來一瓶
- I don't know you're gonna... - Here you go.
不 不 等等
No, no, wait...
這間房子和這個團隊太棒了 正是應該有的樣子
This house and this team are great. It's exactly what it should be.
我是肖恩·帕克
I'm Sean Parker.
噢 他走火入魔了
Oh, he's wired in.
要的就是這感覺
That's what I'm talkin' about.
愛德華多呢
Where's Eduardo?
他在紐約實習
He got an internship in New York.
愛德華多沒一起來
Eduardo didn't come out?
我只是在那兒擠一下
I was crashing there for a little bit while I'm taking care of some things.
不過她的暑假要過完了 所以她要回父母那
But she's done for the summer so she's back at her parents place.
帕羅奧多無家可歸的流浪漢
Homeless rockstar of Palo Alto.
沒錯
Alright.
你暑假有什麼打算
What your plan for the summer?
馬克
Mark.
不好意思 我在看這個建築
I'm sorry, I was looking at the architecture.
- 我問你暑假有什麼打算 - 我夏天一結束就回學校
- I asked, "what's your plan for the summer?" - I hit school by the end of the summer.
- 我要去下洗手間 - 好
- I'm going to the rest room - Okay.
我跟你一起去
I'll go with you.
- 跟你一起那女生很眼熟 - 很多人都覺得她很眼熟
- Your date looks so familiar to me. - She looks familiar to a lot of people.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
有個斯坦福的工商碩士叫羅伊·雷蒙 想給他老婆買內衣
A Stanford MBA named Roy Raymond wants to buy his wife some lingerie.
但他很害羞 不敢去內衣店買
But he's too embarrassed to shop for it at a department store.
所以他想了個主意 一個讓你感覺不那麼像流氓的高端店
He comes up with an idea for a high end place that doesn't make you feel like a pervert.
他貸款了四萬美金 找親戚又借了四萬美金
He gets a $40,000 bank loan, borrows another $40,000 from his in-laws,
開了家店 叫維多利亞的秘密
Opens a store, and calls it Victoria's Secret.
第一年就賺了五十萬 他做了郵購目錄 開了三家分店
Makes a half million dollars his first year. He starts a catalog, opens three more stores
五年之後他以四百萬美元的價格把公司賣給了Leslie Wexner
And after five years he sells the company to Leslie Wexner and the Limited for four million dollars.
大團圓結局 對吧
Happy ending, right?
只不過兩年之後 那家公司就值五億美金
Except two years later, the company's worth 500 million dollars.
而羅伊·雷蒙跳下了金門大橋
And Roy Raymond jumps off the Golden Gate Bridge.
可憐的只是想給老婆買內衣的男人
Poor guy just wanted to buy his wife a pair of thigh highs.
那是個寓言
Was that a parable?
跟我在一起的姑娘是維多利亞秘密的模特 所以你才覺得她眼熟
My date is a Victoria Secret model. That's why she looks familiar to you.
不用被這嚇到 我看過你的博客
Don't be impressed by all of this. I read your blog.
噢 噢 那都是胡扯
Oh, oh you know, no thats for webprints.
你知道我是怎麼創辦Napster的嗎
You know how I started Napster.
我高中喜歡的那個女生
Girl I love in high school.
和曲棍球隊隊長在一起
Was with the co-captain of The Varsity Lacrosse team
而我想把她從他手媟m過來
And I wanted to take her from him
所以我決定做點大事
So I decided to come up to next big things.
這我倒沒聽說過
I didn't know that.
Napster不是個滑鐵盧 我永遠地改進了音樂行業
Napster wasn't the faillure... I changed the music industry for better and for always.
也許它沒掙什麼錢 但把不少人氣個半死
They might not have been a good business but it piss a lot of people off.
而這正是你的Facemash的特點 它嚇到我了 夥計
And this now what your facemash about, they scare of my pal,
大家都被嚇到了
and they're gonna be scared of you.
那些風險投資者會說 不錯的點子 孩子 剩下的就交給大人們吧
What the VCs wanna to say, good idea kid, grown up so we could take it from here.
不過這次不是 這是我們的時代
But not this time, this is our time.
在這個時代你可以給他們一張名片 然後說"我是首席執行官 婊子"
This time you gonna hand them a business card that says I'm a CEO... bitch.
我就想讓你變成這樣
That's what I want from you.
愛德華多到底在什麼鬼地方
Where the hell was Eduardo?
- 他在紐約 - 去什麼該死的紐約
- He's in New York. - ***
他要去實習
- He's got an... - internship.
這埵酗j把公司 成千上萬的公司
The company's here. A billion dollar company is here.
- 你無法離開Facebook了嗎 - 對
- Do you live and breathe Facebook. - Yes
我知道一定是這樣
I know you do.
愛德華多想做個生意人 我知道他一定可以成為成功的生意人
Eduardo want to be a businessman for all I know he gonna be a good one
但是他不該在紐約卑躬屈膝
but he shouldn't be in New York ***
這是個創意高於一切的時代
This is a once-in-a-generation, "holy shit" idea.
而金門大橋下的水可是冷得像冰一樣
And the water under the golden gate is freezing cold.
看著我 你敢說我說的是胡話嗎
Look at me face tell me I don't know what I talkin' about.
你後來還想過那個女孩嗎
Do you ever thinkin' about that girl...
哪個女孩
What girl?
高中那個和曲棍球隊長一起的女孩
The girl from high school with the Lacrosse team...
沒有
No.
你就不該問"風流肖恩"這個問題
If you guys are gonna talk about bandwidth, we need shots.
- 假期末尾就拓展到百所大學？ - 對
- Hundred schools by the end of the summer? - Yup.
姿態決定一切
I tell you what, gesture of a good faith.
你把它拓展到百所大學 我幫你把它拓展到兩個大洲
While you're getting into a hundred schools, I put you on two continents.
兩個大洲
Two continents.
如果你沒地方擠的話 完全可以來跟我們一起住
If you don't get a place to crash i think you should definitely come in live with us.
不醉不歸
Let's line-up some shots.
服務生
Excuse me...
有什麼需要
Yes, Sir.
把這些收走 來瓶1942年的唐胡媔
You can take this away and bring back Don Julio 1942.
沒問題 卡特先生
Absolutely, Mr. Carter.
英國亨利皇家賽舟會
泰晤士河畔 亨利
- 比賽很不錯 - 謝謝
Thank you.
- 這是我哥哥 卡梅隆 - 很出色
- And this is my brother Cameron. - Excellence.
尊敬的阿爾伯特王子殿下
His Royal Highness, Prince Albert.
殿下 這是卡梅隆和泰勒·溫克艾沃斯
Sir, this is Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss.
是啊 十分出色 我還沒看過這麼激烈的比賽
Of course. Brilliant race. I've never seen a race that close.
- 是的 殿下 - 我的祖父 傑克·克
- yes, sir. - My grandfather, Jack Kelly,
是他那個時代最早一批賽艇隊員之一
was one of the premiere rowers of his day.
我已經三十年一直來看亨利賽艇賽
I've been coming to Henley for 30 years.
從來沒見過這麼激烈的比賽
And I've never seen the race that close.
- 你見過這麼激烈的比賽嗎 - 沒有 殿下
Have you seen a race that close? No, your Highness.
1.5英里的比賽通常可以領先一到兩個船身
Mile and a half races are more commonly won by a boat length or two.
對 完全沒錯 真是激烈啊
Yes, that's absolutely right. Brutally close.
我可以介紹一下其他隊員嗎…
May I introduce my team mates...
- 抱歉我們得先走了 - 非常出色
- I'm sorry you have to excuse us... - Until the Beijing.
- 這麼大老遠飛過來就為了看這個？ - 別管了 老兄
- So you flew out here to see that? - Wouldn't miss you brother.
那個皇室成員怎麼樣
How was the royalty?
他一個勁地說"比賽有多麼多麼激烈"
I just want him to tell me couple more times, how close the race was just brutal, brutally-brutally- excruciating.
坎 那傢伙是一個王子 但那國家跟東漢普頓差不多大 放鬆點
Cam. The guy's the prince of a country the size of East Hampton. Relax. Its fine...
- 孩子們 - 父親
- Boys. - Dad
- 你好 - 你好 溫克艾沃斯先生
-  - Mr. Winklevoss.
剛剛真是惜敗啊
That was a tough beat.
很抱歉讓你和媽媽飛這麼大老遠來看這個
I'm sorry You and Mom flew all over here to see that.
不用為輸了這麼激烈的比賽而向我道歉
Don't ever apologize to me for losing a race like that.
不用為輸了比賽向任何人道歉
Don't ever apologize to anyone for losing a race like that.
孩子們
Boys.
肯萊特先生
Mr. Kenwright.
父親 這是肯萊特先生 我們這周在他那堭H宿
Dad, this is Mr. Kenwright, head of the host family this week.
- 很榮幸見到你 - 很高興見到你
- Pleasure to meet you. - Good to meet you.
我剛剛和我的女兒通了電話
I just had a phone chat with my daughter.
她說她和她朋友們正在談論比賽
She told me that she and her friends are all talking about the race,
她們剛剛在電腦上看了
Which they just seen by the computer.
一個叫Facebook的新網站 美國也有這個網站嗎
A new website called Facebook. Do you have this in America?
我要去找你們的母親了
I'm going to find your mother...
- 有什麼不對勁嗎 - 你女兒不是在美國讀書嗎？
- is it something wrong? - Your daughter doesn't go to school in States?
不不 她在劍橋 學法國文學
No, no. Cambridge. Majoring in French Literature,
- 雖然我覺得這專業不怎麼樣 - 劍橋也有Facebook？
- though I wasn't aware these was such a thing. - They have Facebook at Cambridge?
很顯然牛津和倫敦商學院也有 因為她的朋友們在那
And apparently Oxford and the London School of Economics because that's where her friends are.
那真棒
It's awesome.
精彩的比賽
Good race, boys.
加油
Take the bitter with the better, eh?
我要去一下洗手間
I'm gonna go to rest room.
我要看看
I wanna to see it.
別這樣
Stop it.
別這樣 坎
Stop it, Cam.
別看了
Knock it off.
我不介意以一秒之差輸給荷蘭隊
I don't mind that we loss by the Dutch by less than a second.
那是場精彩的比賽 也是公平的比賽
That was a good race, that was a fair race.
而且他們會再看到我們
And they'll see us again.
我介意 而你也應該介意的是本該在週日的比賽我們週一才知道
What I mind and what you should mind, is showing up on Monday for race which run on Sunday.
我們試過和他談 寫禁制令給他
We tried talking to him ourselves, we tried writing a letter,
我們找過行政委員會 也找過了校長
We tried the Ad Board, and we tried talking to the president of the University.
現在我問你 最後問一次
Now I'm asking you. For the last time.
讓我們用確鑿的證據 把他告到聯邦法庭上去
Let's take the considerable resources at our disposal and sue him in a federal court.
拜託
Come on...
我要去喝一杯
I need a real drink.
去他媽的 我們得把那臭小子幹掉
Screw it, let gut that freaking nerd.
就是要這樣
That's what I'm talking about.
聽著 我今天看見他了
No, I saw him today.
馬寧漢姆 米切爾·馬寧漢姆 他是"追逐…稍等
Maningham, Michael Maningham, my Chase Equity...
你們用了"長釘"或者"幽靈"沒 小姐們 [裝備名稱]
Are you guys using spike or ghost, miss?
不知道 我們只是在互相亂射
We don't know, we're just shooting at each other.
用神風敢死隊吧
Use sweet kamikaze.
鬼知道那是什麼
Like we know what that is.
我看到他開卡雷拉了 他也看見我了
I saw him getting into his turbo carrera, and he saw me too,
我知道他看見了
I know he did.
別 別這樣 等一下
Don't sweat it.
爆頭!
Bong hit.
是不是有人敲門啊
Is anybody hear that banging?
你什麼也沒聽見 你在寫代碼
You don't hear anything, you are writing code.
兄弟 真的有人敲門
Dude, somebody's at the door.
這不是…
It's not a dish best served cold. It's best served immediately and relentlessly.
我一會兒再打給你
I'm gonna call you back.
- 怎麼了 - 怎麼了
- What's up - What's up?
馬克一個小時前就該在機場接我
Mark was supposed to pick me up at the airport an hour ago,
我一直在打他手機
I've been calling his cell.
他之前連續寫了36小時的代碼 所以去小睡了一下
He was on a 36 hour coding tear so he took a nap for a couple of hours.
這媯o生了什麼
What happened here?
不是發生了 是正在發生
Not happened... happening.
下一個大事件
The next big thing.
瓦爾多
Wardo!
嘿 夥計
Hey man.
- 工作 - 好吧
- Back to work. - ok.
不好意思 我吸多了點…
The more bad I get at this, the more wasted I get.
我是說…
I mean the more wasted that I get...
我們知道了
We understand.
她們多大了 肖恩
How old are they, Sean?
問這個不禮貌
It's not polite to ask.
她們多大了
How old are they?
- 你以為你很瞭解我嗎 - 我看過不少關於你的東西
- You think you know me, right? - I've read enough.
你知道我瞭解你多少嗎
You know how much I've read about you?
一無所知
Nothing.
- 瓦爾多 - 嘿 老兄
- Wardo. - hey, man.
我在機場等了你一小時
I waited an hour for you at the airport.
幾點了
What time is it?
午夜 或者紐約時間凌晨三點
It's midnight. Or 3AM in New York where I just came from.
快來看看我們的新東西
You've gotta see some of the new stuff we've got.
嘿 達斯丁 給他看看那個牆 我打算就叫它"牆"
Hey, Dustin, show him the wall. I'm just calling it the wall.
別管那個牆了 跟他說說我安排的那個會面
Forget the wall, tell him about the meeting I've got set up.
- 你知道彼得·提爾嗎 - 不知道
- You know Peter Thiel? - No.
你當然不知道了
No reason you should.
他只不過是擁有價值20億美元的避險基金公司 叫"科拉堮次窶"
He just run a two billion dollar hedge fund called Clarium Capital.
為什麼他在安排會面
Why's he setting up meetings?
提爾也許願意做個天使般的投資
Thiel may want to make an angel investment.
我不管他是不是天使 為什麼他在安排會面
I don't care if he's an actual angel, why's he setting up business meetings?
你飛機坐太久了
You've had a long flight.
不 我在肯尼迪機場通道等太久了
No, I've had long wait on the tarmac at JFK,
在行李區等太久了 然後才飛得太久
Then a long wait at the passenger between there was a long flight.
我不停地為我們跑生意
I run the business end of this company,
而他只是個免租房客
he's a house guest living here rent-free
由愛德華多·薩佛林基金慷慨贊助的房子
On a very generous grant from Eduardo Saverin Foundation.
我聽說過你有錢的老爸 名牌燕尾服 選修哈佛調酒課程
I heard about you big ticket advice, Gerry's tuxedos, Harvard Bartending Course.
你離包餅乾就只有一步了 我能感覺到
You're just one small step away from bagging Snookies Cookies, I can feel it.
我能單獨和你談一會麼
Can I talk to you alone for a minute?
沒問題
Sure.
爆頭
Bong hit!
你怎麼樣
How's it going?
實習怎麼樣 克奡絡汐晹n嗎
How's the internship? How's Christy?
實習怎麼樣？
How's the internship?
對
Yeah.
馬克 上帝 我退出了實習
Mark, Jesus, I quit the internship.
我在電話上跟你說過 我第一天就退出了
We've talked about this on the phone, we... I quit on my first day.
我記得你說過了
I do remember you saying that.
那克奡絡托蝏羆
So, how's Christy?
她瘋了
She's crazy.
好笑嗎
Is that fun?
不 她確實很神經質 超級愛吃醋
No. She's actually psychotic. She's insanely jealous,
她不理智 我有點被嚇到
She's irrational and I'm frightening of her.
不過有女朋友還是挺好的
Still, it's nice to have a girlfriend.
我不想讓那個人把自己當成這公司的一份子
I do not want that guy representing himself as part of this company.
你應該搬來 瓦爾多 這是奇跡發生的地方
You gotta move out here, Wardo, this is where it's all happening.
- 你聽到我剛剛說什麼了嗎 - 那種聯結的感覺 那種能量…
- Did you hear what I just said? - The connections, the energy...
馬克 馬克
Mark...
我怕你如果不搬來的話 就會被我們落下了
I'm afraid if you not come out here. You gonna left behind.
我想 我想…我需要你…
I want, I want, I need you.
- 搬來 - 你剛剛說什麼
- Out here, please don't tell me... - What you just say?
這一切比我們預想的發展得快太多
Its moving faster than any of us ever imagine...
- 太快了 - 你說什麼
- It's moving fast. - What did you mean?
- 比肖恩想的還要快 - 肖恩不是公司的一份子
- It's moving fast then Sean think... - Seans is not part of the company.
- 我們已經有30萬會員 覆蓋160個學校 - 我知道
- We've got over 300.000 members, we're in 160 schools... - I'm aware of that.
- 還有五個在歐洲 - 我知道 馬克 我是財務總監
- Including five in Europe... - I'm aware of that, Mark, I'm the CFO.
我們需要更多程序員 也需要更多錢
We need more programmers. And we need more money.
他安排了Thiel的會面 他安排了和各種人的會面
He set up the Thiel meeting. He's set up meetings all over town.
- 他還安排了其他會面？ - 對
- He's set up other meetings? - Yes.
- 而我對此一無所知？ - 你人在紐約
- Without me knowing anything about it?! - You're in New York!
我在紐約一天搭14小時地鐵 去給我們找…
I'm in New York riding subways 14 hours a day try to find our...
有什麼成果嗎
How's it going so far?!
你說"被你們落下"是什麼意思
What did you mean get left behind?
我能幫到你嗎
Can I help you?
我想凍結這個賬戶 取消所有支票和信貸額度
I'd like to freeze this bank account and cancel all existing checks and lines of credit.
請出示身份證
May I see some ID please.
可以
Yeah, sure, sorry.
- 肖恩 他們馬上就可以見你們了 - 沒問題
- Sean they will be right with you... - No problem.
你知道嗎 "火燒摩天樓"就是在這堜蝒
You know this is where they filmed Towering Inferno.
真犀利
That's comforting.
朋友們 隨我進來吧
Guys... come at my back.
- 她給你們拿水了嗎 - 噢 我們很好
- She offer you some waters? - Oh, yeah we're cool.
請進吧
Come on in.
- 你一定是馬克 - 你好
- You must be Mark. - Hi.
我們看了所有的資料 恭喜你們
We took a look everything and congratulations.
我們會先給你們提供50萬美金的投資
We're gonna start you off with a $500.000 investment.
馬奡絲|跟你們談關於公司重組的事
Maurice is gonna talk to you about some corporate restructuring.
我們會在特拉華州註冊一個集團
We'll file as a Corporation in Delaware
然後建構新的股份結構 以便讓新的投資者加入
and come up With a stock structure to allow for new investors in.
現在我要問你一些問題
Now lemme ask you something.
愛德華多·薩佛林是誰
Who's Eduardo Saverin?
上帝
Jesus chris...
- 你什麼時候回來的 - 你嚇死我了 以後要敲門
- When did you get back? - You scared me. I need you to knock.
你 什麼時候回來的
When-did-you-get-back?
- 今天下午回來的 - 那你打算什麼時候打電話給我
- I got back this afternoon. - And when you gonna call me?
克麗絲 旅途很辛苦 我很累…
Chris... it was kind of a rough trip and I was tired and...
或者回我發的47條短信的一條 你知道我發了47條短信嗎
Or answer one of my 47 texts? Did you know I sent 47 texts?
我知道 我覺得那算是正常現象
I did and I thought that was incredibly normal behavior.
你是在諷刺我嗎
Are you mocking me?
我給你帶了個禮物
I brought you a present.
為什麼你的Facebook主頁上狀態是"單身"
Why does your status say "single" on your Facebook page?
什麼？
What?
為什麼你Facebook主頁上 情感狀態寫的是"單身"
Why does your relationship status say "single" on your Facebook page?
我建那個主頁時我確實是單身
I was single when I set up the page.
而你都懶得去改一下？
And you just never bothered to change it?
- 我… - 說啊
- I... - What?!
我不知道怎麼改
I don't know how.
你是不是覺得我很傻
Do I look stupid to you?
不 冷靜點
No. Calm down.
你是讓我相信Facebook的財務總監
You're asking me to believe that the CFO of Facebook,
竟然不會改他Facebook主頁上的情感狀態？
Doesn't know how to change his relationship status on Facebook?
這很尷尬 所以你應該認為我不會拿這撒謊
It's a little embarrassing so you should take it as as sign of trust that I would tell you that.
- 去死吧 - 別激動
- Go to hell. - Take it easy.
你沒改是因為那樣你每次去看馬克時 就可以跟那些硅谷的蕩婦亂搞了
You didn't change it so you could screw those Silicon Valley slut every time you go out to see Mark.
這完全不是事實 我可以保證
That is not ever remotely true and I can promise you...
那些硅谷蕩婦才不管你Facebook上的情感狀態
That the Silicon Valley Slut don't care what anyone's relationship status is on Facebook.
- 拜託你拆禮物吧 - 你的電話還能用嘛
- Please open your present. - Your phone does work.
是馬克
It's Mark.
好吧 這真棘手 拆禮物吧 是條絲巾
Okay, this is gonna be tricky. Open your present. It's a silk scarf.
- 你看我圍過圍巾嗎 - 都會有第一次的
- Have you ever seen me wear a scarf? - This'll be your first.
- 喂 - 你凍結了我們的賬戶？
- yeah. - You froze our account?
- 沒錯 - 你凍結了賬戶
- I did. - You froze the account.
我要引起你的重視 馬克
I had to get your attention, Mark.
你意識到你這是危及整個公司的嗎
Do you realize that you jeopardized the entire company?
你意識到你的行為 可能會把我所有的努力毀於一旦嗎
Do you realize that your actions could've permanently destroyed everything I've been working on?
是我們的努力
WE've been working on.
沒有錢 網站就無法運作
Without money, the site can't function.
讓我告訴你Facebook和其他網站的區別吧 那就是它永遠不會崩潰
Ok let me tell you the different between Facebook and everybody else, we don't crash ever.
只要服務器哪怕崩潰一天 我們的名聲就全毀了
If the servers are down for even a day, our entire reputation is irreversibly destroy.
- 聽著 - 真的 Friendster的失敗就證明了這一點
- Look... - Seriously, I think Friendster prove that!
就算是很少的人離開 也會對整個用戶群造成巨大的影響
Even a few people leaving would reverberate through the entire user base.
用戶是互相連通的 這是關鍵
The users are interconnected, that's the whole point!
大學生在線是因為他們的朋友在線
College kids are online because their friends are online.
這就像多米諾骨牌效應 你明白了嗎
And if one domino goes, the other dominoes go!
我再也不想去什麼 猶太兄弟會的"加勒比之夜"了
I'm not going back to the Carribean Night at A-E-Pi.
老天爺啊
Holy shit...!
- 你搞什麼飛機 - 你喜歡被人無視嗎
- What's wrong with you! - Did you like being nobody?!
你喜歡被當作笑話嗎 你想回到那種生活嗎
Did you like being a joke? Do you wanna go back to that?!
等一下 等一下
Hang on, hang on...
那是幼稚的行為 不是個成熟男人的作為 而且肯定不是一個朋友的作為
That was the act of a child, not a decent man. And it truly wasn't the act of a friend.
你知道我今天去取錢的時候有多難堪嗎
You know how embarrassed I was when I tried to cash a check today?
我不要回到那種生活了 也許你很沮喪
I'm not going back to that life. Maybe you were frustrated.
對
yeah.
- 也許你很生氣 - 我確實很生氣
- Maybe you were angry, - I was.
不過我不介意讓一切都隨風而去 因為我有好消息要告訴你
But I'm willing to let bygones be bygones because I've got a good news.
我很抱歉 我當時很生氣 可能也太幼稚了
Look, I'm sorry. I was angry and maybe it was childish.
但我想引起你的注意
But I had to get your attention.
愛德華多 我說我有好消息要告訴你
Eduardo, I said I've got some good news.
什麼好消息
What is it?
彼得·提爾決定給我們五十萬美金的天使投資
Peter Thiel just made an angel investment of a half million dollars.
- 什麼 - 五十萬美元
- What? - half million dollars
而且他會給我們辦公室
And he's setting us up in an office.
他們要重組公司
They want to re-incorporate the company,
他們想見你 而且需要你簽一些文件
They want to meet you and they need your signature on some documents.
所以快點做第一班航班到舊金山來 我需要我的財務總監
So get your ass on the first flight back to San Fransisco. I need my CFO.
我馬上就到
I'm on my way.
- 瓦爾多 - 在
- Wardo. - Yeah.
這是我們的成果
We did it.
瓦爾多
Wardo,
你已經要回去了嗎
You're going back there already?
對
Yes.
還有 我要跟你分手
And also I'm breaking up with you.
四份文件 頭兩份是股份收購協議
Four documents. These first two are common stock purchase agreements,
可以讓你購買重組後的Facebook的股份
Allowing you to buy stock in the newly re-incorporated Facebook
也就是說舊的股份現在已經沒有價值了
as supposed the old share which is now worthless.
第三份是交換協議
The third is the exchange agreement,
你可以用舊股份換新股份 最後一份是股東投票協議
Allowing you to exchanges the old shares for new shares and then finally voter holding agreement.
我會有多少股份？
How many shares of stock will I own?
- 1,328,334美元 - 上帝啊
- 1.328.334 - Jesus Christ.
大概是34.4%的股份
That's a 34,4% ownership share.
為什麼他們在原有的30%上增加了
Why they increase from the original 30%?
因為你們可能會稀釋原有股份 以用股份吸引新的投資者
Because you may need to dilute it to award shares to new investors.
- 我真喜歡跟學商的人合作 - 是啊
- I love working with business majors. -
- 學經濟的 - 對
- Economics. - right.
你應該知道馬克的股份已經從60%降到51%了
You should know that Mark's already taken his percentage from 60 down to 51.
馬克不在乎錢 而且他需要保護
Well, Mark doesn't care about money and he needs to be protected.
達斯丁·莫斯克維茨擁有6.81% 肖恩·帕克有6.47%
Dustin Moskowitz owns 6,81%, Sean Parker 6,47%
可以接受 還有彼得·提爾占7%
I can live with that. And Peter Theil 7%
要用我的筆嗎
Would you like to use my pen?
愛德華多？
Eduardo?
你能重複一遍問題嗎
Can you please repeat the question?
不 那種尖銳的問題問一次都是可恥的
No. It was an outrageously leading question, the first time.
而你現在還想再聽一次？
Now you want to hear it twice?
你能重複一遍嗎
Would you re-read that please?
問吧
Go ahead.
你在簽署這些文件時
And when you signed these documents,
有沒有意識到你是在簽下自己的死亡證明
Were you aware that you were signing your own death certificate?
沒有
No.
當時我沒有請律師來檢查一遍那些文件 我真是太愚蠢了
It was insanely stupid of me not to have my own lawyer look over all the... uh,
說實話我當時就覺得他們是我的律師
In all honesty I thought they were my lawyers.
我是你唯一的朋友 你只有一個朋友
I was your only friend. You had one friend.
- 我父親都不再理我了 - 愛德華多
- My father won't even look at me. - Okay. Eduardo.
扎克伯格先生在你簽文件後說了什麼嗎
Did Mr. Zuckerberg saying anything to you after you signed the papers?
當時不停握手 祝賀之類的
There was a lot of handshaking and a lot of congratulations.
他告訴了我 他至少有一學期不能回學校
He'd already told me he wouldn't be coming back to school for at least a semester.
所以我們還道了一下別
So we were saying goodbye for a while.
- 然後在我走之前 他說… - 但你必須回來
- And then before I left, he said... - But you gotta come back.
十一月末十二月初的時候
Somewhere around the end of November or early December.
彼得想等我們用戶突破百萬時 搞個盛大的慶功宴
Peter wanna throw us an amazing party when we hit a million members,
絕對是空前的 你一定要回來參加
It's gonna be out of control. You gotta come back for it.
一百萬用戶
A million members.
對
Yeah.
還記得宿舍窗上的運算法則嗎
The algorithm on the window at Kirkland?
是的
Yeah.
是的 我會來參加的
Yeah, I'll be here.
- 你確定我要這麼做嗎？ - 你遲到了20分鐘
- You sure about this? - You're 20 mins late.
你要進去 說你睡過頭了 沒時間整理著裝
You're gonna walk in there and say you overslept and you didn't have time to get dressed.
他們會央求你的
They're gonna pitch you.
"追逐平等"會央求你收下他們的錢
Chase equity is going to pitch you. They're gonna beg you to take their money.
你就點頭 點頭 點頭 然後說
You're gonna nod, you're gonna nod, you're gonna nod and then you're gonna say,
"你們誰是拉爾夫"
"Which one of you is Ralph"
不 不是拉爾夫… 是馬寧漢姆 你們誰是米切爾·馬寧漢姆
No, not Ralph... No Manningham. Which one of you, Michael Manningham?
然後他會說 "是我"
And he'll say I am.
然後你就說 肖恩·帕克說"草泥馬" 然後你就走出來
Then you'll say, Sean Parker says "Fuck You." Walk out.
好
Okay.
十一月下旬我收到馬克的郵件 讓我去參加百萬用戶慶功宴
In late November I got the e-mail from Mark telling me to come out for the millionth member party.
那封郵件還說什麼了？
What else did e-mail say?
還說我們要開個工作會議
It said that we had to have a business meeting.
馬克和肖恩對Chase Equity 玩了某種報復小把戲
That Mark and Sean had playing some kind of revenge stunt to Chase Equity.
馬寧漢姆印象深刻 所以他開出了難以拒絕的條件
Manningham was so impressed that he was makin' an investment offer that was hard to turn down.
於是我就去了加州 直接去了新公司
I went out to California and I went straight to the New Offices.
我不知道該打扮成去參加派對 還是去開會 所以我就摻雜了兩者
I didn't know whether to dress for the party or the business meeting so I kinda dressed for both.
不過這不重要
But it didn't matter.
為什麼
Why not?
因為我不是因這兩個原因被叫去的
Because I wasn't called out there for either one...
你是為什麼被叫去的呢
What were you called out there for?
伏擊
An ambush.
薩佛林先生 你好
Mr. Saverin. Hi...
過來這邊
Hey. Right over here.
起初我以為他是開玩笑 要給我簽更多的合同
At first I thought he was joking, giving me more contracts to sign.
但之後我開始看條款
But then I started reading.
這是什麼
What is this?
你知道我們有一些新的投資者
Well, as you know we had some new investor that...
這是什麼
What is this?
薩佛林先生
Mr. Saverin.
馬克
Mark...
馬克!
MARK...!
- 他很忙 - 是嗎
- He's wired in. - Sorry
他很忙
He's wired in.
- 是嗎 - 是的
- Is he? - Yes.
那現在呢 你還忙嗎
How about now, you still wired in?
叫保安
Call security!
你發行了兩千四百萬新股票
You issued over 24-million new shares of stock.
之前告訴過你如果有新的投資者…
You were told that if new investors came along...
你的股份會被稀釋多少？ 他的呢？
How much your shares are diluted? How much are his?!
扎克伯格先生的股份稀釋到了多少
What was Mr. Zuckerberg's ownership share diluted down to?
沒有稀釋
It wasn't.
莫斯克維茨先生的股份稀釋到了多少
What was Mr. Moskowitz's ownership share diluted down to?
沒有稀釋
It wasn't.
肖恩·帕克的股份稀釋到了多少
What was Sean Parker's ownership share diluted down to?
沒有稀釋
It wasn't.
彼得·提爾的股份稀釋到了多少
What was Peter Thiels's ownership share diluted down to?
沒有稀釋
It wasn't.
你的股份稀釋到了多少
What was your ownership share diluted down to?
百分之零點三
Point-zero-three-percent.
- 你簽了那些文件 - 你給我下了套
- You signed the papers. - You set me up.
你是因為你是這公司的財務總監
You blame me because you were the business head of the company,
卻把自己的財務搞砸了才來怪我嗎
And you made a bad business deal with your own company?!
這就好像我不是Facebook的一份子
It's gonna be like I'm not part of Facebook.
不會好像你不是Facebook的一份子 你確實不是Facebook的一份子
It won't be like you're not a part of Facebook, You're not part of Facebook.
我的名字在首頁上
My name's on the masthead.
你可以再看看
You may wanna check again.
是因為我凍結了賬戶嗎
This is because I froze the account?
你覺得我們會讓你 穿著可笑的西裝招搖過市
You think we were gonna let you parade around in your ridiculous suits,
假裝你在運營這家公司嗎
Pretending you were running this company?
真不好意思啊 我的普拉達還在乾洗店
Sorry, my Prada is at the cleaners,
和我的風衣還有'草泥馬'人字拖一起 你們這些虛偽的孬種!
Along with my hoodie and my 'Fuck You' Flip-Flops, you pretentious douche bag!
- 保安來了 你最好離開這 - 我不會簽那些文件的
- Security is here. You'll be leaving now. - I'm not signing those papers.
我們會拿到你的簽名的
We will get your signature.
告訴我這不是因為我進了鳳凰社
Tell me this isn't about me getting into the Phoenix.
是你幹的 我就知道是你幹的 那隻雞是你設計我害我的
You... you did it. I knew you did it. You planted the story about the chicken.
我沒有用雞來設計害你
I didn't planted the story about the chicken.
- 他在說什麼 - 你指控我虐待動物
- What he talking about? -
真的 這雞是怎麼回事
Seriously, what the hell with the chicken?
我相信你最痛恨的
And I'll bet what you hated the most,
就是他們還把我寫成Facebook的創始人之一
They said they identified me as a co-founder of Facebook.
而我正是 你最好快點請律師 渾蛋
Which I am! You better lawyer-up, asshole,
因為我不會為了30%回來 我要拿走我應得的一切
'Cause I'm not comin' back for 30% I'm comin' back for everything!
- 把他帶出去 - 沒事 我自己走
- Get him outta here. - It's okay. I'm going.
等等
Hang on...
差點忘記了
Almost forgot.
這是你的19000美元
Here's your $19.000.
但我沒法兌現它 因為賬戶被你凍結了
I wouldn't cash it though. I drew it on the account you froze.
我很喜歡站在你旁邊 肖恩
I like standing next to you, Sean.
顯得我特別爺們兒
It makes me look so tough.
今晚的表演到此結束 各位
That's it. That's our show for tonight, people.
我想看到大家盡情享受派對
Look, I want to see everybody here get geared up for a party.
我們要像梅西百貨感恩節遊行一樣 走進那家酒吧
We're gonna walk down to the club like it's the Macy's Parade.
瑪奇 放大屏幕 我們馬上就要破百萬了
Mackey, put it up on the big screen, we've gotta almost be there.
- 你還好吧 - 嗯
- You alright? - Yeah.
你有點過分了
You were kinda rough on him.
這就是現實的人生
That's life in the NFL.
- 你知道你可以不用那麼過分的 - 聽著 馬克 我只是…
- No. You didn't have to be that rough on him.
肖恩
Sean...
- 你可以不用那麼過分的 - 他差點毀了公司
- You didn't have to be that rough on him. - He almost killed it!
我會給他送花道歉的
I'll send flowers.
說到花 今天的派對結束後 女生那邊還要搞個派對
Speaking of flowers, I'm putting together a party after the party at Kappa Eta Sigma.
艾斯麗是其中之一
Ashleigh there's a sister.
艾斯麗？
Ashleigh.
- 實習生 - 對
- The Intern. - yeah.
我知道她是誰
I know who she is.
你是不是…
Are you guys?
艾斯麗和我？ 沒有 好吧 有一點…
Ashleigh and me... no... A little bit.
怎麼了
Why?
打擾一下 馬克
Excuse me, Mark.
我們正說到你呢
We were just talkin' about you,
你工作做得很出色
You're doing a really good job.
謝謝 我很榮幸
Thanks. I appreciate that.
這是給你的
This came in for you.
放我桌上吧
Put on my desk.
這包裹是什麼
What's the package.
沒什麼
Nothing.
瑪奇
Mackey...
是
Yes, Sir.
刷新
Refresh!
我知道你不喜歡擁抱
And you need a hugger, I know.
一百萬
1 millions,
誰有香檳
who's got champagne?
下一步計劃是做一個照片分享的應用
...A pic sharing application.
一個可以在社交圈堣嬤伢茪貜漲a方
A place where you view pictures that coincide with your social life.
是你生活的數字化真實寫照
It is the true digitalization of your life.
- 看到了嗎 - 看看我美不美
- You can use a CD. - You can do it off of me.
你不需要去參加派對 你可以用相機參加派對
You don't just go to a party anymore, you go to a party with your digital camera,
而你的朋友就可以在網上重現派對
And then your friends re-live the party online.
還可以加標籤 這創意…
And tagging. The idea...
把罩罩脫了會不會更方便
Would this be easier without the bra?
可以試試看
It's worth finding out.
關掉音樂 立刻!
Stop the music, now!
我花了很多時間研究人們登錄後都做什麼
I've spent hours... watching what people do when they log on
他們怎麼查看好友的狀態更新
They check friends status update,
好奇怪 音樂怎麼沒了
That's weird, why the music off...
查看那些好友修改了資料 換了照片以及…
Checked to see which of their friends had changed their profiles, changed their photos and mostly...
說真的 音樂怎麼了
Seriously, what happen with the music
我們在農場生活過 後來生活在城市 而我們現在要生活在互聯網絡上
We lived on farms, and then we lived in cities and now we're going to live on internet
肖恩 打住 我覺得樓下有什麼事
Sean. Stop, I think something's goin' on downstairs.
注意一下
Please...
各回各家吧
Time to go home!
派對結束了
Party is over.
- 警察 - 靠
- It's the cops! - Shit.
很高興見到你 警官 有什麼能幫到你們的嗎
Good to see you officer... What can I do for you.
發生了什麼事
What's goin' on?
是因為音樂太吵了嗎 我們正在慶祝
Was the music too loud? We were havin' celebration.
小姐 請扣上襯衫扣子
Miss, I need you to button your blouse.
我可以讓他們把音樂關小點
I can tell them to turn the music down...
那不是我的
That's not mine.
我們需要查驗身份 把手放在看得見的地方
Ok, we gonna need identification, keep your hand where we can see 'em
噢 天啊
Oh, my God.
你口袋埵釣S有藏什麼東西
Anything else in your pocket, I should know about?
沒有 長官 沒有
No, Sir. No.
- 別犯傻 - 不會 我…
- Don't be stupid now. - I don't, I...
這是什麼
What this
那是腎上腺素
That's an Epipen.
- 這個呢 - 是我的吸入器
- And this? - That's my inhaler.
你多大了
How old are you?
21歲
I'm 21
- 21歲 - 21歲
- 21. - 21.
我21歲了
I'm 21
說謊只會更糟
Lying only would make it worst!
對不起 我不該撒謊的
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have lied.
- 喂 - 聽著 出事了…
- Hello? - Listen, something's happen...
該死
Shit.
沒事的 沒事的 我已經保釋了
It's alright, it's gonna be alright. I've posted bond.
我什麼也沒做 我有過敏反應…
I wasn't doing anything. I mean, I've got allergies...
- 實習生 - 這只是個派對
- Interns... - It was just a party
這會是頭條 肖恩
This gonna be news, Sean.
隨時都有可能在網上傳開
It's gonna be online, any second.
- 我知道 - 你知道 跟一個實習生…
- I know. - You know with an intern...
沒事的 一切盡在我掌握之中
It's cool, I have it under control
一切在我的掌握之中
I will get it under control.
我會打電話看看下一步怎麼行動
I will call someone and see what the next move is.
但這事很快就會傳開去
But this gonna be news now.
你覺不覺得是愛德華多在搗鬼
You don't think Eduardo was involve, do you?
- 你這麼覺得嗎 - 不
- Do you think? - No.
或者馬寧漢姆 他們其中之一有人 有人把可卡因拿了過來
Or Manningham, one of them, somebody, somebody sent the cocain there, 'cause it got in there.
相信我 會沒事的
You believe me, it's gonna be fine...
對吧？
Right?
回家吧 肖恩
Go home Sean.
"我是首席執行官 婊子"
馬克
Mark...
今天的環節已經結束了
We're done for the day
嗯 我只是在這坐坐
Yeah, I was just sittin'...
肖恩怎麼樣了
What happened to Sean?
他還是有公司7%的股份
He still owns 7% of the company.
你一整天就只吃了那點沙拉 你要不要去吃點東西
All you had all day only was that salad, you wanna get something to eat?
不用了
I can't.
我不是壞人
I'm not a bad guy.
我知道
I know that.
帶有感情色彩的證詞 我覺得85%帶有誇張成分
Under emotional testimony, I assume 85% of it is exaggeration.
- 還有15%呢 - 偽造
- And the other 15? - Purgery
神話媮`是有魔鬼
Creations myth needs a devil.
目前怎麼樣了
What happens now?
塞和其他人去大學路上吃牛排了
Sy and the others are having a steak on University Avenue.
然後他們就會回辦公室
Then they'll come back up to the office...
然後做代表你庭外和解的準備工作
And start working on a settlement agreement to present to you.
他們要和解？
They're gonna settle?
對 而且你還得額外付一點錢
Oh yeah... and you're gonna have to pay a little extra.
為什麼
Why?
這樣這些人才會簽保密協議
So that these guy sign an non-disclosure agreement.
他們只要公開說你一句壞話 你就慘了
They say one unflattering word about you in public, you own their wife and kids.
我創造了Facebook
I invented Facebook
我在說陪審團
I'm talking about what a jury.
我專門挑選陪審團成員
I specialize in voir dire... Jury selection.
陪審團看到被告時看的是什麼
What a jury sees when they look at the defendant.
衣服 頭髮 說話方式 是否討喜
Clothes, hair, speaking style, likability...
討喜？
Like-ability?
我考到律師證已經20個月了
I've been licensed to practice law for all of 20 months.
我可以讓陪審團相信
And I can get the jury to believe...
是你用雞設計害了愛德華多
That you planted the story about Eduardo and the chicken.
看著 比如這樣
Watch, what else?
你那天晚上為什麼不在肖恩的派對上
Why weren't you at Sean's sorority party that night?
你覺得是我叫了警察？
You think I'm the one that called the police?
無關緊要 我問了這個問題 大家開始思考這個問題
Doesn't matter, I ask the question, now everybody's think about it
你頭十分鐘就失去了陪審團的信任
You've lost your jury in the first 10 mins.
- 家畜 - 沒錯
- Farm animals? - Yeah.
我喝醉了 很生氣 很愚蠢
I was drunk, and angry and stupid.
- 寫日誌… - 寫日誌
- And blogging... - and blogging.
給錢吧 不過就是張超速罰單而已
Pay them, on the scheme of things. It's a speeding ticket.
明天塞會說一樣的話
That what Sy will tell you tomorrow.
有人會介意我在這用一下電腦嗎
Do you think anybody would mind if I stay and use the computer for a minute...
應該不是問題
I can't imagine that would be a problem.
謝謝
Thanks.
謝謝你今天的幫助
I appreciate your help today.
你不是個渾蛋 馬克
You're not an asshole Mark...
你只是太努力地想要變成個渾蛋
You're just trying so hard to be...
"申請加為好友"
"發送申請"
卡梅隆和泰勒·溫克艾沃斯接受了
6500萬的庭外和解 並簽署了保密協議
Cameroon and Tyler Winklevoss received a settlement of 65 million dollars and signed a non-disclosure agreement.
他們代表美國隊參加北京奧運會划艇比賽 取得第六名
They rowed for the U.S. Olympic Team in Beijing and placed sixth.
愛德華·薩佛林收到了未知數額的庭外和解
並且他的名字保留在了Facebook首頁的創始人欄
Eduardo Saverin received an unknown settlement. His name has been restored to the Facebook masthead as a Co-Founder.
Facebook在207個國家擁有五億用戶
目前市場價值已達250億美元
Facebook has 500 million members in 207 countries. It's currently valued at 25 billion dollars.
馬克·扎克伯格成為世界上最年輕的億萬富翁
Mark Zuckerberg is the youngest billionaire in the world.